I've started seven businesses that have
我创办了七家公司，它们
gone 0 to a million in their first 12
在头12个月就实现了从零到百万的营收，其中
months three businesses that went north
三家更是超过了
of 10 million but here's a crazy thing
1000万。但令人惊讶的是，
anyone can do this and I'm going to take
任何人都能做到这一点。我会一步一步地教
you step by step through the best ways
你如何赚到足以
to start making that life-changing
改变人生的
amount of money Daniel pry money and
巨额财富。我是丹尼尔·普莱，一位理财和
business Expert that's helped thousands
商业专家，他帮助成千上万的
of people start scale and grow their own
人从零开始，创建并发展壮大了自己的数
multi-million pounds businesses from
百万英镑企业。
scratch these are the best ways to start
以下是一些最佳的创业方法：
a business we start with an idea but we
我们从一个想法开始，但我们
need to sharpen our ideas in the market
需要在市场上验证我们的想法，而
not in our minds I see so many people
不是仅仅停留在脑海中。我看到很多人
that raise money book an office buy
筹集资金、租办公室、购买
computers but after all of that no one's
电脑，但最终却没有人
interested in their idea so we have to
对他们的想法感兴趣。所以我们必须
conduct tests where we fail fast and
进行测试，快速且
fail cheap for example waiting lists is
低成本地失败。例如，候补名单是
one of the fastest ways to test an idea
测试想法最快的方法之一，
and this is what really smart
真正聪明的
entrepreneurs do like Elon Musk launched
企业家都会这样做。比如，埃隆·马斯克
a waiting list for the model 3 he
为Model 3推出了候补名单，
launched a waiting list for the Cyber
为Cyber​​truck推出了候补名单，验证了这个想法。
truck validating the idea in fact Rolex
事实上，劳力士在
stopped selling Rolexes and they started
停止销售劳力士手表并开始
selling the waiting list but if it's
销售候补名单时取得了巨大的突破。但如果最终无人问津，那也没关系。
crickets okay fair enough let's have
我们再来谈谈
another idea but what if someone steals
另一个想法，但如果有人窃取了
my idea ideas aren't worth anything the
我的想法怎么办？想法本身毫无价值，
value is for the person who does it what
价值只属于创造它的人。
are the fundamentals of being an
成为一名
exceptional salesperson pitcher first
杰出的销售员/推销员的基本要素是什么？首先，
you will have to you said business is a
你必须……你说过，商业是一项
team sport is there anything you found
团队运动。你有没有发现，在
best people you've partnered with so
你合作过的所有优秀人才身上，有什么共同点？
here's what I'm looking for and there's
这就是我正在寻找的，还有很多内容需要探讨，
a lot more to go through but one of the
但
other strategies for building a business
建立业务的另一个策略
is and that should get you into the six
是……仅仅做到这一点，就能让你获得六位数的
figures of Revenue just by doing that
收入。
it's shocking because it's so simple
这令人震惊，因为它如此简单。我们来
let's talk about money let's talk about
谈谈钱。
if someone's out there and they've got
假设有人有
£100 or £1,000 worth of disposable
100英镑或1000英镑的可支配
income what should I be about to making
收入，他应该如何实现
myself financially free the truth is
财务自由？事实上，
that there's incredible wealth to be
这里蕴藏着巨大的财富
created one of the biggest opportunities
创造空间，这是目前世界上最大的机遇之一。令
is it's absolutely crazy to me that so
我感到不可思议的是，
many of you have decided to watch our
你们中有这么多人决定观看我们的
show um and so many of you have decided
节目，这么多人决定
to subscribe to our show we now have
订阅我们的节目。我们现在
five million subscribers on YouTube
在YouTube上有500万订阅者。 这
which is a number that I just can't
是一个我简直无法
comprehend and it's a dream that I
理解的数字，也是我以前想都不敢想的梦想。
absolutely never could have had we
我们
started the dire of a CEO just over 3
三年前创办了“CEO的困境”这个节目，
years ago now and in my wildest
我最乐观的
expectations we might have had 100,000
预期是现在能有10万
subscribers by now so you can imagine
订阅用户。所以，你们能想象
how shocked I am that so many of you
我有多么震惊吗？竟然有这么多人
conversations every week um and spend
每周都收听我们的节目，花
some time with us so thank you and I
时间和我们一起交流。非常感谢你们！
made a deal with you I made a deal that
我和你们达成了一个协议：
if you subscrib to this show that we
如果你们订阅这个节目，我们
would continue to raise the bar and in
会不断提升节目质量。
2024 we're going to raise the bar like
2024年，我们将把节目质量提升到
never before I've been working for the
前所未有的高度。过去
last nine months on a surprise for all
九个月，我一直在为所有订阅用户准备一个惊喜，现在
and I'm very excited to deliver that for
我非常激动地要和
you the Productions going to change
大家分享。节目的制作方式将会改变，
we're going to go even further with our
我们会和嘉宾进行更深入的交流，
guests and we're going to tell even more
讲述更多
Global stories so as always if you
全球性的故事。所以，和以往一样，如果你
appreciate what we're doing here the
喜欢我们的节目，
simple free favor I'll ask from you is
我唯一的小请求就是
to hit the Subscribe button let's get on
点击订阅按钮。让我们开始吧！
[Music]
【音乐】
Daniel if someone has just clicked on
丹尼尔，如果有人刚刚点击收听
this
这个
podcast can you tell me the reason why
播客，你能告诉我
they should stay around and listen and
他们应该留下来继续听下去的理由，以及
what you think they're going to get from
你认为他们会从
this conversation I think we're living
这次对话中获得什么吗？我认为我们正经历着
history never before have people had the
历史上最不可思议的时代，人们从未有
opportunity to build something that is a
机会打造一个
global business full of fun freedom and
充满乐趣、自由和
flexibility full of passion and
灵活性、充满激情和
purpose and today that is accessible to
目标的全球性企业。如今，
almost anyone who'd be listening to this
几乎所有收听这个
podcast the Baby Boomers they got access
播客的人都能做到这一点。婴儿潮一代获得了负担得起的
to affordable housing we get access to
住房，而我们现在也获得了负担
Affordable Global small businesses
得起的全球小型企业。
now the entrepreneurial journey is scary
创业之路对
to a lot of people but if you conduct
很多人来说都很可怕，但如果你进行
the right experiments have the right
正确的尝试，拥有正确的
mindset follow the right process it's
心态，遵循正确的流程，那么
entrepreneurship and I think anyone
创业其实是可预测的，而且对人们来说是安全的。我认为任何
who's listening to this is going to see
收听这个播客的人都会意识到，创业是
that it's a lot more process driven then
一个过程驱动的过程，
I think that we can go step by step to
我们可以一步一步地
build a business that you absolutely
打造一个你绝对热爱的企业。
conversation in an hour's time or two
在这次对话结束后，无论是一个小时、两个
hours time or you know whenever this
小时，还是无论何时结束，
podcast finishes what are they going to
他们都会
have that they didn't have before this
获得什么之前没有的东西呢？
we're going to talk about the
我们将探讨
entrepreneurial Journey as a set of
创业之旅，将其视为一系列
steps predictable steps and they're
可预测的步骤，并提供
going to be able to have a map of how do
一张路线图，指导您如何完成
you move through that entrepreneurial
这段创业之
Journey like what do you do first what
旅，例如：第一步做什么？
do you do next how do you go to the next
下一步做什么？如何提升到更高
level and scale up and who do you
层次并扩大规模？以及应该联系谁？这套路线图是基于我与
coming across thousands and thousands of
成千上万处于创业旅程
entrepreneurs at each stage of the
各个阶段的企业家的深入交流而总结出来的。
journey so ideally what I want people to
因此，我希望大家最终能够清晰地了解
around how this entrepreneur thing works
创业的运作方式，
and who are you what's your experience
以及您自身的情况和经验。
so my backgr is over 20 years of
我的背景是超过20年的
Entrepreneurship I started my first
创业经验。我21岁时创办了我的第一家
company when I was 21 years old I did 2
公司。19岁到21岁期间，我曾为
years working for a mentor from 19 to 21
一位导师工作了两年，
uh we built a business from scratch to
我们从零开始打造了一家年
millions of Revenue I then left that
收入数百万美元的企业。之后我离开了那位
Mentor I went out on my own started my
导师，开始独立创业，创办了
own first small business uh it grew very
自己的第一家小型企业。这家企业发展迅猛，
the first year and then 10 million in
第一年就从零增长到一百万美元，第三年又增长到一千万。此后，
year three I've started uh seven
我又创办了七家
businesses since that have gone Z to a
企业，每家企业的年收入都达到了零到一
million in their first 12 months I've
百万美元。 在最初的12个月里，我帮助
done three businesses that went north of
三家企业实现了超过
10 million and what about this
1000万英镑的营收。关于这个
accelerator I I read that you have an
加速器，我听说你有一个
accelerator where you have thousands and
加速器，
thousands of entrepreneurs who come to
成千上万的创业者来到
your accelerator for business advice
这里寻求商业建议和
coaching from getting from zero to you
指导，从零开始，逐步发展到
know up on that um up to their
他们理想的职业
trajectory yeah so 12 years ago I
轨迹。是的，12年前，我
noticed this trend um around this idea
注意到
of global small businesses and I
全球小型企业的兴起，我
basically saw that technology was making
意识到科技让
it possible for anyone to do the things
任何人都能做到跨国公司才能做的事情。于是
doing and I started an entrepreneur
我创办了一个创业
accelerator designed for people to
加速器，旨在帮助人们成为
positions as a key person of influence
关键的影响力人物，
to build their personal brand to build a
打造个人品牌，组建
core team of people around them to
核心团队，将
digitize the value that they offer um
他们提供的价值数字化，
and to take the most or make the most of
并充分利用
the times that we're living in and since
我们所处的时代。从那时起，
then about 4 and a half thousand
大约有4500家
companies have gone through this whole
公司经历了整个
process um we've seen people go from
过程。我们见证了人们从
zero to multi- multi-million pound exits
零到数百万英镑的退出，
we've seen people build the business of
我们见证了人们建立
their dreams where they get to live and
梦想中的事业，让他们可以随时随地生活和
work from anywhere and you know we've
工作。我们
also seen what people struggle with and
也看到了人们遇到的困难。
what they've found difficult we've gone
我们和
with our clients it's dancing classes
客户一起经历了疫情、全球金融危机以及所有这些挑战，这就像
for entrepreneurs it's it's a high
为企业家开设的舞蹈课，这是一个高
performance environment where you get to
绩效的环境，在这里你可以和志同道合的
be around people who want the same sort
人在一起，学习一些
have some accountability some best
最佳
practices uh you get a community or a
实践，建立一些责任感，融入一个社群或人脉
network around you uh and you go through
网络，并与
that entrepreneurial Journey with other
其他正在经历创业之旅的
people who who are going through it as
人一起成长。
well do you think anyone can be an
你认为任何人都可以成为
entrepreneur I think entrepreneurial
企业家吗？我认为创业
spirit is something that we're all born
精神是我们
with um entrepreneurship is this idea
与生俱来的。创业精神是指
that we want to create value for others
我们想要为他人创造价值，
that we want to take a little bit of a
想要承担一些
creative risk that we want to do
创造性的风险，想要做
something that represents
一些能够表达
self-expression there are different
自我的事情。创业之旅有不同的
stages to the entrepreneurial journey
阶段，
and everyone can go through those stages
每个人都可以经历这些阶段。而且，
entrepreneur there are people who are
企业家并非只有一种类型，有些人
very good at Finance there are people
擅长财务，有些人
who are good at operations there are
擅长运营，有些人富有远见，有些人
people who are doers and get the stuff
是实干家，能够把事情
done and there are businesses that suit
做好。不同的企业
those types of people so it's about
类型也适合不同的人。 关键在于
finding out who you are finding out what
了解自己，了解什么
kind of business would actually be well
样的生意真正
suited to that person and then making
适合自己，然后
sure that you're doing the thing that
确保自己做的是真正适合自己的事。那么，
you're you're well suited to how does
如何判断
one know that a business would be suited
一个生意是否适合
to them CU if you
自己呢？如果你
you know gauged on the the people that
观察
come up to me in the street or the taxi
街上遇到的陌生人、出租车
drivers I speak to or my friends or the
司机、朋友，或者我收到的
DMS that I get everyone's got an idea
邮件，你会发现每个人都有想法，
nobody seems to be short of ideas but so
似乎没人缺乏想法。但
many people seem to be stuck at that
很多人却在
moment of making a decision to pursue a
决定是否要追求
particular idea that they almost get
某个想法的那一刻卡住了，几乎陷入了停滞不前的状态。
like paralysis like sofar preneurs you
就像那些创业者一样，
know all of their ideas stay on the sofa
他们所有的想法都停留在最初构思的沙发上，
that they were um conceived on but they
却
because of like that paralysis I don't
因为这种停滞不前而迟迟无法行动。我不
know if this is the one I get that the
知道我理解的那个
time is this the idea the the thing is
想法是否正确。关键在于，
we need to sharpen our ideas in the
我们需要在市场上磨砺我们的想法，而
market not in our minds so what we have
不是仅仅停留在脑海中。所以我们必须
to do is go make contact with other
去接触其他
people and see what they say and see
人，听听他们的想法和意见。
what they think so we have to conduct uh
因此，我们必须进行
tests where we fail fast and fail cheap
测试。 如果一定要失败，我们会快速失败，而且失败成本要低。
if we fail at all so here's an example
举个例子，
of what I like to do when someone has an
当有人提出
idea I say set up a very simple waiting
想法时，我喜欢先创建一个非常简单的候补
list landing page and essentially let
名单页面，告诉
people know I'm thinking of starting
大家我正在考虑
something in this particular space or
在这个领域开展一些项目，或者
we're launching something in this space
我们将在
later in the year if you're interested
今年晚些时候推出某个项目。如果你感兴趣，
join the waiting list now that waiting
现在就加入候补名单。候补
list concept essentially if people will
名单的概念很简单：如果有人
join the waiting list and if you get
加入，而且有
hundreds of people joining a waiting
数百人加入，
list it's a pretty good indication that
这就能很好地表明
it is a good good idea uh if you launch
这是一个好主意。但是，如果你创建了
a waiting list and you message 3,000
一个候补名单，并向3000
people and say I'm launching I'm
人发送消息说“我要
launching this thing do you want to join
推出这个项目了，你们想加入
the waiting list and no one joins then
候补名单吗？”，结果却无人加入，
it's a good indication that's not the
这说明这个
idea right cuz we have to have a good
想法可能行不通。因为我们必须将我们
marriage between what we're passionate
热衷的事情、
about what we want to do and what the
我们想做的事情与
market wants um there's 6 million
市场需求完美结合。
businesses in the UK 30 businesses in
英国有600万家企业，美国有3亿家企业，
the USA and that basically means there's
这意味着
a lot of businesses doing a lot of
很多企业都在做很多
things that already exist so the market
已经存在的事情，所以市场
might not have an unmet need the market
可能并不需要这些。 市场可能存在未被满足的需求，比如“
might say hey I already have a great
嘿，我已经有很棒的
cupcake Supply there's already someone
纸杯蛋糕供应商了，
who makes great coffee in my
我家附近已经有很棒的咖啡店了，
neighborhood we don't need another one
我们不需要再多一家了”，
okay fair enough let's have another idea
好吧，没问题，那我们再想想别的点子吧？
right you can always have plenty more
你总是有很多
ideas so you got a test the faster you
想法的，所以你可以做个测试。你越快
can get on with conducting a fast and
进行快速且
cheap test the better you're going to
低成本的测试，
you know go with your entrepreneurial
你的创业
idea because that's one of the big sort
想法就越有可能成功，因为
of mental barriers that people have is
人们面临的一大心理障碍是，
they see that committing to any of these
他们意识到投入任何
ideas is going to cost them three years
想法都会耗费他们三年时间、
their reputation and potentially
声誉，甚至可能损失
hundreds of thousands of their money or
数十万美元的资金，或者
or an Investor's money so that again
投资者的资金。这再次
creates paralysis because the discomfort
造成了瘫痪，因为
associated with being wrong when you
当你
think there's so much on the line will
觉得风险如此之大时，那种害怕犯错的不安感会让
hold you in place but your idea there of
你止步不前。但你的想法是，
just throwing up a landing page
直接搭建一个落地页，立刻就能解决问题。
immediately kills the Paris and also
而且，
just a landing page of a waiting list so
仅仅搭建一个候补名单的落地页，
you're not even saying that this thing's
你甚至都没说这个项目
are dead certain you're just saying
十拿九稳，你只是说，
we're going to be launching something if
如果
we get enough interest um and here's the
我们有足够的兴趣，我们就会推出产品，嗯，这是
waiting list and by the way this is what
候补名单。顺便说一句，这才是
really smart entrepreneurs do like Elon
真正聪明的做法。 像埃隆·
Musk launched a waiting list for the
马斯克这样的企业家确实会这么做：他为Model 3推出了预订名单，
model 3 he launched a waiting list for
为Cyber​​truck推出了预订名单，
the Cyber truck I think he launched a
我想他还
waiting list for a flamethrower I joined
为火焰喷射器推出了预订名单。我加入了
all waiting lists yeah and he he's you
所有预订名单。是的，你
know he's essentially what he's doing is
知道，他本质上是在用一种
a very smart process of validating the
非常巧妙的方式来验证想法。
have as an early stage entrepreneur is
作为早期创业者，我们最好的心态之一就是像科学家一样
the mindset of a scientist conducting a
进行
little experiment and what we're trying
小实验。我们努力
to do is not be emotionally attached to
做到的不是对结果抱有情绪上的执念，而是要说：
know what if people don't like this okay
如果人们不喜欢这个，没关系，我会想出
I'll have another idea if people do like
另一个主意；如果人们喜欢，
this I'll go to the next step um so a
我会进入下一步。所以，
scientist is just kind of like
科学家就像是在
conducting an experiment and the best
做实验，而最好的
experiments are cheap and fast a waiting
实验是成本低、速度快的。预订
list is probably the most powerful early
名单可能是
stage experiment you could um you could
你能做的最有效的早期实验。你可以
go with Elon Musk when he launched the
看看埃隆·马斯克推出
cybertruck I don't think there would
Cyber​​truck预订名单的那次。我想当时地球
have been an investment Bank on the
上应该没有哪家投资银行会
planet that would have backed a factory
投资一家生产
cybertruck but when he walked in and
Cyber​​truck这种东西的工厂，但是当他走进工厂的时候……
said I've got a million people who have
我说，有一百万人已经
put down a $100
交了100美元的
deposit if only 5% of them go ahead they
定金，即使只有5%的人继续，他们也
can crunch the numbers on that and say
可以计算一下，然后说，
yeah okay we'll fund that fair enough
好的，我们投资，没问题，那就开始
let's build it um so it's very powerful
开发吧。这非常有效。
I did this recently I I had my team come
我最近就做了这件事。我的团队找到
up to me and say hey we could do a
我说，嘿，我们可以围绕一个人工智能
startup around um an AI that helps
创业，这个人工智能可以帮助
people write a book and um I said well
人们写书。我说，
I'm not sure if anyone would like that
我不确定是否有人会喜欢，
but let's launch a waiting list so I
但我们可以先建立一个候补名单。所以我
launched a waiting list put one post on
建立了一个候补名单，在LinkedIn上发布了一条消息，结果有
LinkedIn 750 people joined the waiting
750人加入了
list list I was expecting
候补名单，而我原本预计只有
150 uh and in the waiting list we
150人。在候补名单中，我们
actually asked questions like how much
提出了一些问题，比如
would you pay for it per month and how
你每月愿意支付多少钱，
many months do you think it would take
你认为需要几个月才能完成，
you and what would success look like and
成功是什么样的，
what would failure look like and what
失败是什么样的，
else would you try instead of this if
如果
this didn't exist what would you use so
没有这个产品，你会尝试什么，你会用什么。
we asked all these questions we
我们问了所有这些问题，
collected a ton of data uh and then off
收集了大量数据，然后根据这些数据制定了
product I also went to Angel Investors
产品规格。我还去找了天使投资人。
and said do you guys want to co-invest
然后我说，你们想不想共同投资
in this one we raised £300,000 on the
这个项目？我们通过SEIS计划筹集了30万英镑，
valuation for an idea no lines of code
估值300万英镑，而这只是一个想法，没有代码，
nothing built nothing designed uh and
没有开发，没有设计。
essentially we got ourselves ready to to
基本上，我们
launch in a couple of months just simply
仅凭着
off the back of that waiting list and
那份等候名单和
all the data that we uh that we
我们收集的所有数据，就做好了几个月内启动的准备。这很
collected so interesting the the other
有意思。
point you said within there was about
你刚才提到的另一点是关于
you said there's kind of two things what
两件事：
you're passionate about and what the
你热衷的事情和
market wants now on the point of passion
市场需要的事情。说到热情，
it's so cliche people say follow your
人们常说“追随你的
passions do things you're passionate
热情，做你热衷的事情”
about Etc how role how important do you
等等，这真是老生常谈了。你
think the role of passion is in actually
认为热情在
succeeding at any of these ideas so if
实现这些想法的过程中究竟有多重要？假设
I've got four ideas cupcake business
我有四个想法：纸杯蛋糕生意、花店生意、
floristry business soccer business and I
足球生意，还有
don't know AI
人工智能
business what role does my own intrinsic
生意。我对
passion of any of these areas matter in
这些领域的内在热情在
success passion matters a lot because
成功的几率中扮演着怎样的角色？热情非常重要，因为
business is hard and you have to stick
做生意很艰难，你必须坚持下去，克服困难。
with it through the Downs so the reason
所以
passion is valuable is because you are
热情之所以有价值，是因为你会经历这一切。
going to go through valleys um and
低谷，嗯，
they're going to be painful and they're
它们会很痛苦，而且
going to be the the gratification is
满足感会
going to be very much delayed uh in any
延迟很久，嗯，在任何
business Journey so passion is the thing
商业旅程中都是如此。激情是让
that gets you through it's not the thing
你坚持下去的东西，它不是让
that you ride high on it's the thing
你飘飘然的东西，而是让
that you get through the hard times with
你度过难关的东西。
um I have a very weird definition of
嗯，我对激情的定义很特别，
passion I kind of like tried to strip it
我试图把它剥离
back to its bones and I look for an
到最本质的东西，我寻找的是
alignment between origin mission and
起源、使命和愿景之间的一致性。
vision so I essentially say what is your
所以我基本上会问，你的
origin story what's your background I
起源故事是什么？你的背景是什么？我
want to see that you're doing something
想看到你正在做的事情与
that aligns to what you've always been
你一直以来
doing I want to see that this goes back
所做的事情一致。我想看到这件事可以追溯到你
to age 10 um for me when I ask people
10岁的时候。嗯，对我来说，当我问别人
about why you're doing this thing I want
为什么要做这件事时，我希望
them to start the story a long time ago
他们从很久以前就开始讲述这个故事，
and I want them to tell me about little
我希望他们告诉我他们一路走来取得的小小
wins that they've had along the way that
胜利，这些胜利最终促成了他们现在的
they're starting this business to me
创业之路。对我来说，这
that's great because anything that we
很棒，因为任何我们反复
keep coming back to as a recurring theme
提及的主题，都是
is what we're meant to be doing so for
我们应该做的事情。
me I've going right back to age 10 I
我的经历可以追溯到10岁，从
teenage years and going back to age 10
青少年时期一直到10岁，都与“商业向善”这一理念息息相关。
good um and it goes right back to a
这可以追溯到
garage sale that I did when I was 10
我10岁时举办的一次车库甩卖。当时
years old we had a house fire it was a
我们家遭遇了一场火灾，那是一段
horrible experience but it turned into a
可怕的经历，但它最终却变成了一次
positive experience because I set up
积极的经历，因为我举办了
this garage sale and made some money and
这次车库甩卖，赚了一些钱。
something bad happened and I turned it
我把不幸的遭遇转化为了
into something good through business and
积极的商业机会。
for me there's this recurring theme that
对我来说，
all of my little winds line up to these
我所有的小小灵感都与这些
these themes so the origin story is
主题相契合，这其中蕴含着一个反复出现的主题。所以，我的创业故事
really powerful the vision for the
非常有力。
future is what do I want to see happen
我对未来的愿景是：
in the future if all of this goes well
如果一切顺利，
and other people are doing it too what
其他人也在做同样的事情，那么
would this look like in the future what
未来会是什么样子？
would 10 years from now 20 years from
10年后、20年后，
now be if we were celebrating what would
如果我们庆祝，
we love to be celebrating and then the
我们最想庆祝的是什么？而我的
mission is what is the most high value
使命则是：我能做的最有价值的事情是什么，并且
alignment with that Vision so
与我的愿景相符？
essentially if there is a strong
本质上，如果
alignment between origin mission and
创业的使命和
vision something happens where you you
愿景高度契合，那么你就会以一种
carry yourself in a different way you
不同的方式行事。
you you sit differently you speak
你坐姿不同，说话方式也
differently you're you're in this
不同，你与他人保持一致，
alignment other people pick up on it
其他人会注意到这一点，
they want to quit their job and come and
他们想辞掉工作
work on your team um they hear about the
加入你的团队。他们听说了你的
vision they hear about your origin story
愿景，听说了你的创业故事，
they hear about the mission and they go
听说了你的使命，然后他们会说：“
oh I'm going to leave what I'm doing and
哦，我要离开现在的工作，
come and join that and that's the magic
加入你们。”这就是
of Entrepreneurship so for me that's
创业的魔力。对我来说，这就是
passion it's not about like
激情。它不是那种
superficially I like snowboarding or um
肤浅的爱好，比如“我喜欢滑雪”或者“
oh I've always enjoyed baking a cake
我一直很喜欢烤蛋糕”，
it's the uh alignment of origin mission
而是创业的初衷、使命
and
和
vision interestingly there um I was
愿景的契合。有趣的是，我一直在
trying to think about what the opposite
思考
of everything you've said just looks
你刚才说的所有内容的反面是什么。
like what's the opposite of passion in
在
your definition what's the misalignment
你对激情的定义中，激情的反面是什么？不契合又是什么样子？
look like so can you give me a an an
你能举个
example of what the opposite of that
例子说明一下吗？比如，
definition looks like the opposite is I
我
heard about some guy who pumped a
听说有人靠
cryptocoin and made millions of dollars
炒币赚了数百万美元，
so I want to go and find out how to pump
所以我也想去学学怎么炒
crypto coins or uh I heard someone who
币；或者，我听说有人
made money flipping property so I need
靠炒房赚钱，所以我也想去
to flip property and I'm going to do a a
炒房。 我要去上个
course on Flipping property I've got no
房产翻新课，我对
interest in property
房产一点兴趣都没有，
uh I've never been interested in
呃，我从来没对
property I've never shown any interest
房产感兴趣过，我对这些东西也从来没表现出任何兴趣。
in in any of these things I just want to
我只是想
make money and it's got nothing to do
赚钱，这
with my background I've got no little
跟我的背景无关，我
wins in this I I have no real vision for
在这方面没有任何小成就，除了致富之外，我对未来没有任何真正的愿景。
the future other than being rich um so
所以，
essentially this is of no value to
基本上，这对
anyone listening no one cares in fact
任何听众来说都没有价值，没人关心。事实上，
when people hear that they're repulsed
当人们听到这些时，他们大多会感到反感。
by it in most cases just hearing someone
大多数情况下，听到有人
talk about that makes you feel I
谈论这些会让你觉得“我
definitely don't want to see you for the
绝对不想在
next two years why are they destined to
接下来的两年里见到你”。为什么他们注定要
fail because they can't attract a team
失败？因为他们无法吸引
team uh essentially all of business and
团队。团队，呃，本质上，所有的商业和
life is a team sport and it's your
生活都是团队运动，你
ability to attract great talented people
吸引优秀人才的能力，以及他们
around you who want to work with you
愿意与你共事的能力，
that is ultimately the reason we succeed
最终才是我们成功的原因，
and it's ultimately the reason we feel
最终也是我们感觉
good so if you're saying things that
良好的原因。所以，如果你说的话让人
repulse people then talented people
反感，那么有才华的人就会
leave and talented people don't want to
离开，他们就不想
be involved if you're saying something
参与其中。如果你说的话能引起
that feels resonant that it feels
共鸣…… 感觉一切都很
aligned and it feels like um something's
契合，感觉好像有什么事正在
happening it feels like this guy's up to
发生，感觉这个人
something or this you know this woman is
或者这个女人在
up to something she's in rolling people
筹划什么，她正在努力让人们理解
in this Vision that she's got and people
她的愿景，人们
love her story it's destined to succeed
喜欢她的故事，这注定会成功，
because good people are getting involved
因为优秀的人正在参与，
and more and more good people are
而且越来越多的优秀人正在
getting involved do you knowing what's a
参与。你知道什么是
good opportunity and what's not a good
好机会，什么是坏
opportunity do you think that when
机会吗？你觉得
you're younger you should be saying yes
年轻的时候应该对更多的事情说“是”吗？因为像
you're in now you're bombarded with
你现在这样，机会多得让你应接不暇，
opportunity so you have to use a kind of
所以你必须运用一种
a different mental framework yeah do you
不同的思维模式。是的，你
think when people are younger they
觉得年轻人
should have a different bias towards
应该对接受机会有不同的偏好吗？
accepting opportunities or [__]
或者应该多尝试，多探索，多摸索？是的，
we we should definitely go through that
我们当然应该经历那个
phase um and also be willing to say oh
阶段，也要勇于承认“哦，
that wasn't it I'm going to stop and go
那不是我想要的”。 我要停下来，去
try something else so you dropped out of
尝试其他的事情。所以你从
University I dropped out of University I
大学辍学了，我也从大学辍学了。我曾经对上
was so excited to go to university and
大学充满热情，
then as soon as I realized it's this is
但当我意识到这不是
not going where I want to go I had to
我想要的生活时，我不得不
make the decision to leave all my
做出离开所有
friends um and walk away from University
朋友、离开大学的决定。
that that sort of dark Valley you have
那种
make the decision to leave the um well
离开
worn track of University or corporate
大学、公司
job or the 9 to5 that how how does one
工作或朝九晚五的熟悉道路时，你必须经历一段黑暗的迷茫期。一个人该如何做好
prepare mentally like what's the mindset
心理准备？那种决定“我要穿过荆棘丛生的
through the bushes and be lost and find
灌木丛，迷失方向，然后找到
my own way I always enjoyed all of this
自己的路”的人，他们的心态是怎样的？顺便说一句，我一直很享受这一切。
by the way so the my mindset was that I
所以我的心态是，我一直很
was always quite excited that um being
兴奋，因为
lost I felt was probably going to be
我觉得迷失可能是这个
part of the process I have a simple view
过程的一部分。我对心态有一个简单的看法，
around mindset which is you're either
那就是你要么像
being a reptile an autopilot or a
爬行动物一样，像自动驾驶一样，要么像
Visionary what's that reptile thing you
远见卓识的人一样。你提到的爬行动物模式是什么意思？它的
mentioned what's the definition of that
定义是什么？
oh well reptile mode is fight flight
哦，爬行动物模式是指战斗、逃跑、僵住、
freeze freak out um throw Tantrums uh be
惊慌失措、投掷。 发脾气，呃，
angry at the people you should not be
对不该
angry at um feels unfair that the
生气的人生气，呃，感觉
world's against you um all of that and
全世界都在与你作对，呃，所有这些，还
the Visionary what the definition of
有远见者，它的定义是什么？
that so the Visionary I don't know if
远见者，我不知道
you've had these moments where you feel
你是否有过这样的时刻，感觉
anything is possible um and you feel
一切皆有可能，呃，感觉视野
very expansive um you think in long time
非常开阔，呃，你的思考着长远，
frames so you think in maybe 10 20 years
比如你会考虑10年、20年
out you also might see the World As One
后的事情，你可能还会把世界看作一个
Small Place so you might uh mentally
很小的地方，呃，
your mental model might be that the
你的思维模型可能是，
world is just one little ball that flies
世界只是一个围绕太阳运转的小球，
everywhere and that there are
到处都是市场，到处都是
opportunities everywhere and that there
机会，到处都是
are people trying to get stuff done and
努力做事的人，
I could have a business that's anywhere
我可以在任何地方创业，
you feel a sense of love and compassion
你会感受到爱、同情
and optimism uh and you typically uh
和乐观，呃，而且你通常会
become more influential in your circles
在你的圈子里变得更有影响力。
the other strange thing about the
关于
Visionary mindset is that um they did
远见者思维的另一个奇怪之处在于，呃，他们
some research with Indian farmers and
对印度农民做了一些研究，
they found that uh these particular
他们发现，呃，这些
people they got paid their yearly salary
农民的年薪是
in one lump sum and then they had to
一次性支付的，然后他们必须让这笔钱维持
make that last for the whole year and as
一整年的生活。 当
they were getting close to the end of
他们接近
that cycle they had uh an IQ test which
那个周期的尾声时，他们做了一次智商测试，结果
showed that they were 15 points of IQ
显示他们的智商比
lower than when they had just been paid
刚拿到那笔一次性付款时低了15分。
the lump sum so the lump sum allowed
那笔一次性付款让
them to think long term it allowed them
他们能够进行长远思考，让他们
to feel affluent and abundant and their
感到富裕和富足，他们的
IQ the scores on the IQ test went up
智商测试分数也因此上升了。然而，
then by the time the money had run out
当钱花光了，
and they you know not sure whether
他们甚至不确定
they're even going to make it to the
自己能否撑到
next one their emotional intelligence
下一个周期时，他们的情商和
their actual IQ intelligence had dropped
实际智商都
significantly so one of the things that
显著下降了。所以，
is a real challenge if you're doing it
如果你正在经历困境，真正的挑战之一
tough is that you're essentially
就是你
regularly putting yourself into these uh
经常把自己置于这种智商极低的
situations where your IQ is right down
境地，你的
um your your emotional intelligence and
情商和
your IQ suffers as a result of being in
智商都会受到影响，因为你处于一种原始的本能状态。
reptile mode I remember a time where I
我记得有一次我
got a parking ticket for
收到了一张
$40 and I I freaked out like I flipped
40美元的停车罚单，我当时吓坏了，真的崩溃了，
out I had a massive fight with my friend
我和朋友大吵了一架。
and um you know like I was in a place
你知道，当时
where $40 was was seriously an issue um
40美元对我来说意味着什么。 这确实是个问题，嗯，
and I remember thinking I'm just going
我记得当时我想，我打算连续
to eat cereal for for weeks um to try
几周只吃麦片，嗯，就为了
and get through this um and so full
熬过这段时间，嗯，完全进入了
reptile meltdown mode what would the uh
崩溃模式。那么，
Visionary have responded to the parking
有远见的人会如何看待这张停车
ticket well the Visionary has a
罚单呢？有远见的人对
different view of life and the the first
生活有着不同的看法。首先，
thing is that if a resource exists on
如果地球上任何地方存在某种资源，那么这种
the planet anywhere that resource is
资源
really just a couple of conversations
实际上只需要几次对话就能获得。
away so essentially a Visionary would
所以，有远见的人会
say well someone's got $40 I just have a
说，有人有40美元，我只要
talk with them and and see what they
和他们聊聊，看看他们需要什么，
need and I'll help them with whatever
我就会帮他们做任何
they need they can help me with the $40
他们需要的事情。他们也可以帮我解决
that I need um maybe I need to wash
我需要的40美元，嗯，也许我需要帮
their car maybe I need to you know help
他们洗车，也许我需要帮
them with their video editing or
他们剪辑视频
something so the Visionary is all about
什么的。所以，有远见的人认为，
the planet that it's just a gray Zone
地球上的资源之间并没有太多的界限，只有关于
around who owns what and Who's got what
谁拥有什么、谁有什么东西的灰色地带，
and we can just have conversations about
我们可以就此进行对话。
that so Visionaries can easily raise
因此，有远见的人很容易筹集
money and raise funds because they just
资金，因为他们会
think well someone's got the money and
想，有人有钱，
they want to put it to use so I'll just
他们想把钱用起来。 我
give them a plan as to how we're going
会给他们制定一个计划，说明我们如何
to put it to use there's a great story
利用这些资源。
that I love which is I think it was the
我特别喜欢一个故事，好像是《壮志
producers of Top Gun were creating these
凌云》的制片人当时正在制作
little models of airplanes and boats and
飞机和船只的小模型，
they're trying to figure out how they
他们想看看如何
would do like a Star Wars style Top Gun
拍一部类似《星球大战》风格的《壮志凌云》
movie and someone said have we actually
电影。有人问：“我们有没有
called the and us whether we can use
联系过他们，看看能不能用
their planes and their boats and
他们的飞机和船只？”
everyone's like no it's like well
大家都说没有。于是有人说：“
they've got planes and boats let's see
他们有飞机和船只，我们去问问
if they want to do it so they ring up
他们愿不愿意。” 于是他们像往常一样给海军打了电话，
general and the general says oh yeah we
和一位将军谈了谈。将军说：“哦，是的，我们
want to enroll more people in the Navy
想招募更多人加入海军，
so we would love for you to make a
所以我们非常希望你们能拍一部
Hollywood Blockbuster film what do you
好莱坞大片，你们
need and they basically say well here
需要什么？” 他们基本上是说：“给你，
have the Jets have the boats have the
喷气式飞机、快艇、
aircraft carriers what whatever you want
航空母舰，你想做什么都可以。”
to do so it's kind of weird to think
想想看，
that someone woke up this morning with
有人今天早上醒来就拥有了
the resource that you want and if you
你想要的资源，如果你和他们
have a conversation about how that
讨论一下如何
resource gets used right essentially you
使用这些资源，这感觉真的挺奇妙的。基本上，你
are now as it's as good as you having
现在就相当于拥有了这些资源。
the resource someone woke up with an
假设有人一觉醒来发现自己拥有一艘
aircraft carrier if you've got a good
航空母舰，如果你能好好
use for that aircraft carrier why not
利用这艘航母，为什么不
have a conversation about how that
讨论一下它
aircraft carrier gets used today it's
如今是如何被使用的呢？这听起来很
shocking because it's so simple and and
不可思议，因为道理其实很简单，
but it's so resonant with me there's two
但却让我感触颇深。
examples I'll give the first I've talked
我举两个例子。第一个例子我已经讲过
about many times was when I was 16 17 in
很多次了。当时我16、17岁，读
six form saw Carly Stoke sat in front of
六年级，看到卡莉·斯托克坐在
me who was a girl in my school I think
我前面，她是我们学校的一个女生，我记得
she was head girl but she was picking
她好像是学生会主席。她当时正在挑选
get in the school and in my brain I
学校要引进的自动售货机。我当时
thought um we have 2,000 paying
就想，我们学校有2000个付费
customers here surely there's a vending
学生，肯定有自动
machine company that would love to put
售货机公司愿意
these machines for free and give us a
免费提供这些机器，然后给我们
cut went to the computer room sent five
分成。于是我去了电脑室，当天就
emails based on Google search rankings
根据谷歌搜索排名发了五封邮件。
our head of keystage 5 has confirmed
我们五年级的负责人斯普林克先生在
this on live TV someone showed up with a
电视直播中证实了这件事。后来有人带着
tape measure to fit the machines because
卷尺来测量机器尺寸，因为
one of my emails had gone to a former
我的一封邮件发给了我的一个以前的
student who was now the CEO of a vending
学生，他现在是一家自动售货机公司的CEO，
machine company and he had been looking
他一直在寻找合适的机器。
to give back to the school example uh B
为了回馈学校，举个例子，呃，B 就
comes in that one yeah did you feel what
出现了。是的，你有没有感受到
it felt like to be a Visionary where
成为“远见者”的感觉？感觉就像
it's like anything is possible like why
一切皆有可能，比如，为什么
are we not just of course we've got
我们不能……当然，我们有
2,000 CL like like did you feel cuz you
2000 CL，就像……你有没有感觉？因为你肯定
in your life you've had reptile moments
在生活中体验过“爬行动物”和“远见者”的转变。你肯定有过“爬行动物”的时刻，
where you're like 100% I hate everyone I
你会百分之百地恨所有人，
want to kill everyone you know and then
想杀了所有人，你知道吗？然后
you've had moments where it's like oh
你也会有这样的时刻：哦，
you know we can bend the world yeah we
你知道，我们可以改变世界，是的，我们
we can bend reality exactly we have
可以改变现实，没错，我们会
conversation about how reality works and
讨论现实是如何运作的，然后
we'll just you know bend it yeah and so
我们就可以改变它。所以
my question has always been like where
我的问题一直是，这种想法从何
does that come from because is I view
而来？因为我认为
our beliefs all of our beliefs as a
我们所有的信念都是
stack of evidence we either have or
一堆证据，我们拥有或
don't really have and for me the
不拥有这些证据。对我来说，作为
youngest of four siblings I had so much
四个兄弟姐妹中最小的一个，我小时候
space compared to my siblings when I was
比我的兄弟姐妹拥有更多的空间，所以
young that I got to like we said earlier
我可以像我们之前说的那样，到处乱跑，到处
like [__] around and find out I got to
探索，我可以
conduct experiments and that led me to
做实验，这让我
believe that the world is bendable I
相信世界是可以改变的。
used to say when I was 14 that if
我14岁的时候就常说，如果
someone said to me that we need to go to
有人跟我说我们
the Moon next week I believe there's a
下周要去月球，我相信肯定有
way cuz I think there's probably a rock
办法，因为我觉得可能已经有火箭发射升空了，
rocket going and all I need to do is
我只需要
contact the person and make a compelling
联系那个人，做一个有说服力的
pitch that's how I get to the the moon
推介，下周就能去月球了。
next week you thought that at 14 yes I
你14岁的时候就这么想？是的，我以前总是
used to say this all the time like my my
这么说。我和同龄人的
difference between myself and my peers
区别在于，
they were academically better but in my
他们的学业成绩比我好，但在我
head there was the only thing that stood
看来，阻碍
in the way of where I am now and where I
我走到今天这一步，以及我未来想去的地方，唯一阻碍我的就是
want to be is a bunch of people bunch of
一群人，无数次的
conversations yeah pitching essentially
对话。没错，推介本质上就是让
pitching is in Rolling people into new
人们接受新的
ideas so what entrepreneurs do to
想法。所以，企业家们为了
advance their ideas is we pitch them
推进他们的想法，会不断地推介，最终让这些想法变成
into existence we start with an idea and
现实。我们从一个想法开始，然后不断地推介它，不断地
we pitch it and we pitch it and we pitch
推介它，不断地推介它，不断地推介
it we sharpen our pitch by talking to
它，通过与人交谈来完善我们的推介。
people but what we're doing that's
但我们所做的
different is we're not just explaining
与众不同之处在于，我们不仅仅是
the idea to people we're trying to
向人们解释这个想法，我们还要努力让
enroll them into that Vision we're
他们认同我们的愿景。我们要让
enrolling people into this Vision that
人们认同我们
we've got for the business and that um
为企业制定的愿景，以及这个
process of getting people to do
过程。 让人们去做他们
thinking they would do that day is
当天醒来时根本没想过要做的事情，这就是
pitching right that's and that's one of
推销，对吧？这是
the first tools that you learn as an
你作为创业者要学习的首批工具之一。
entrepreneur and actually on Dragon's
实际上，在《龙穴》节目中，
Den that is the main tool that people
这也是创业者用来
are given in order to enroll the dragons
说服“龙”们
into investing or getting involved or
投资或参与（或
not so um where does it come from I
不参与）的主要工具。所以，我
think was your question uh I believe
想你的问题是，这种能力从何而来？我认为
it's built into every single individual
它与生俱来，
that it's an evolutionary function that
是一种进化功能。
essentially at the very base of our
本质上，在我们
brain is this reptile mode which is
大脑的最底层，存在着一种爬行动物模式，即
fight flight freeze which is rarely
战斗、逃跑或僵住，这种模式很少
appropriate but in a survival situation
适用，但在生存情况下
probably is appropriate and then there's
可能适用。然后是
autopilot mode which is essentially just
自动驾驶模式，本质上就是
do what you've always done repeat the
重复你一直在做的事情，就像过去一样，
past you know just get into a loop uh if
陷入一个循环。如果
it worked last week and and I didn't die
上周有效，而且我上周没死，那我这
the same week again um and then there's
周就继续这么做。然后是
Visionary mode which is what could I do
愿景模式，即我可以做些什么
different ly what you know what might
不同的事情，有什么
what would be a creative way to solve
创造性的方法来解决
this problem so I feel that a lot of
这个问题。我觉得很多
people think they're missing something
人认为自己错过了什么，
and actually it's all built in and if
实际上…… 这一切都是内在的，如果
you can get yourself into that Visionary
你能让自己进入那种“远见卓识”的
mode often it's the people you hang out
模式，这往往取决于你交往的人、
with um it's the books that you read the
你读的书、
podcasts that you listen to if you can
你听的播客。如果你能
get into that mode then a lot more
进入这种模式，很多事情就
becomes possible you get more IQ points
变得可能了，你的智商和情商都会
you get more EQ points um and you see
提高，你会以一种
the world in a in a very different way
截然不同的方式看待世界。
the key question there is like how do
关键问题在于，
you get into that mode I have a very
你如何进入这种模式？我的
one-dimensional biased um Journey so I'm
经历非常片面，所以我
not sure if my journey is the the best
不确定我的经历是否值得借鉴。
one to take um notes from but from what
但就
I've seen personally people are either
我个人观察而言，人们要么正处于
in some kind of upward spiral towards
某种螺旋式上升的阶段，朝着更具
being more Visionary because it's
远见卓识的方向发展，因为这种上升趋势
compounding in their favor they're
对他们有利。他们
sending the email and then it's working
发送邮件，然后邮件奏效，这
which means they have the evidence to
意味着他们有证据
send more they're more likely to send
发送更多邮件。他们更有可能
emails with more conviction and more
更有信心、更
frequency because it worked last time
频繁地发送邮件，因为上次成功了，
and then more work they get more
然后他们收到更多
responses so they send more emails it's
回复，于是他们发送更多邮件。这是一个
this upward wonderful reinforcing spiral
良性循环的螺旋式上升，
upwards and they become more and more
他们变得越来越有
Visionary like Elon Musk is at the very
远见卓识，就像埃隆·马斯克
top now he's like space ships to Mars
现在处于巅峰一样。 他就像开往火星的宇宙飞船，
yeah he's like chips in your brain that
就像你大脑里的芯片，
monkeys can control computers with
猴子都能用它控制电脑。他处于“
Visionary cycle and at the the bottom of
远见者”周期的顶端，而处于“
the reptile cycle is someone who you
爬行动物”周期底端的人，就是你
know at
在
work the CEO says does anyone want to
工作中认识的那种人。CEO问有没有人想
stand up and share their ideas and they
站起来分享一下想法，他们就
just slouch back in the chair because
懒洋洋地靠在椅子上，因为
they've had their confidence um
他们的自信心受到了
negatively reinforced maybe last time
负面强化。也许上次
they tried it didn't go bad maybe their
他们尝试的时候结果还不错，也许他们的
father or their mother gave them bad
父母某天给了他们不好的
feedback one day and they're in this
反馈，然后他们就陷入了这种
downward spiral where when they do show
恶性循环。当他们
up they show up with low confidence they
出现的时候，他们信心不足，表现
put in a bad performance it goes bad
糟糕，表现更差。
less likely show I would actually call
我其实会把
that autop pilot mode which is I've
这叫做“自动驾驶模式”，也就是“我
never done this before so I won't do it
以前没做过，所以下次我不会再做了”。“
next time um reptile mode is is very
爬行动物”模式极具
destructive you're act you're actively
破坏性，你会主动
breaking your world so it's it's where
破坏你的世界，
you do the worst possible thing okay um
你会做最糟糕的事情。
so you are throwing tantrums and you're
你会发脾气，你会
lashing out against the people who you
攻击那些你本
should you're actually lashing out
不该攻击的人，你实际上是在攻击…… 那些
against the people who are trying to
试图
help you probably um so that's that's
帮助你的人可能……嗯，所以这就是
where you're really at the bottom of
你真正处于“
reptile mode very destructive autopilot
爬行动物模式”最底层，一种极具破坏性的自动驾驶模式。就像
in your situation where you said about
你刚才提到的，
the person who you know is given an
你认识的某个人有
opportunity to speak and they say oh
机会发言，然后他们会说“哦，
well you know it's not what I do is the
你知道，这不是我的风格”，这就是
autopilot response the Visionary is like
自动驾驶模式的反应。而有远见的人会说：“
oh this is a chance to mobilize
哦，这是一个调动
resources um I've got an opportunity
资源的机会，嗯，我在
here to expand my sphere of influence
这里有机会扩大我的影响力范围，
and become a key person of influence in
成为
this room you know so the Visionary is
这个房间里的关键人物。”所以有远见的人会说：“
like oh great this is this is a good
哦，太好了，这是一个很好的
opportunity I can do more with this if
机会，我可以利用它做更多的事情。”如果
the pitch is the keys to everything you
推销技巧是你
want to be because if we were saying
想要成为的一切的关键，因为如果我们说
that it's really conversations that
真正阻碍
stand in the way of where you want to go
你前进的是对话，
and it's the pitch that is essentially
而推销技巧才是通往
the key to wherever you want to go what
任何你想去的地方的关键，那么
are the attributes of a perfect pitch
完美的推销技巧有哪些特点？成为
what are the fundamentals of being an
一名
exceptional salesperson pitcher well
杰出的销售推销员的基本要素是什么？
you've seen some great pictures on the
你在我的博客上看到了一些很棒的图片，
den um lot of bad ones too yeah so
嗯，也有很多糟糕的图片。是的，所以，
here's what I look for clarity is the
我寻找的是清晰度，这是
base level you just don't want to
最基本的。 你不想让
confuse people um Authority is the
人们感到困惑。权威性是指
ability to
能够
communicate that you are worth listening
传达出你值得倾听的信息，
to that there's something about your
你的
background or what you've done or the
背景、你的经历、
data that you're possessing or the
你掌握的数据或
mentor that you've got that gives you
你的导师都赋予了你
some sort of authority to be talking
某种权威性，让你有资格谈论
about this so Clarity and Authority uh
这件事。所以，清晰性和权威性，首先要明确
customer has or some some sort of
客户遇到的问题，或者
problem that exists in the world that
世界上存在的
needs solving and that you've identified
需要解决的问题，以及你已经找到的
an Insight or a solution for that
洞察或解决方案。
problem then the why which I would say
然后是“为什么”，也就是要
is about communicating why you care
传达你为什么如此关心这件事，以至于
enough about this that people would buy
人们会相信你是
into you as the person to drive this
推动这件事
forward you then want to define the
前进的人。接下来，你要定义
opportunity what is the bigger
机会，即参与者能获得更大的
opportunity for anyone who gets involved
机会，以及
the next steps what should someone do
下一步应该做什么。
next and then the emotion or the essence
最后是
that you want to leave people with so
你想留给人们的情感或精髓，让
that they remember you based on that
他们记住你，并基于
essence or that emotion that you made
你带给他们的情感。这就是一个
of a of an inspiring pitch what was the
鼓舞人心的演讲的精髓。
last one there was that the emotion so
最后一个是什么？是情感。所以，
Clarity Authority problem solution the
清晰性、权威性、问题、解决方案、
why opportunity next steps and the
为什么、机会、下一步和
essence and it spells out
精髓，它清晰地阐述了这一点。
Capstone so that's how I remember a
总结一下，这就是我记住
great pitch I've I had to come up with a
精彩路演的方法。我必须想出一个
way of remembering this because I was
记住路演内容的方法，因为我
pitching so often I had to be able to
经常做路演，所以我必须能够
come back to okay how do I pitch this so
回顾一下，我该如何进行路演。所以，
the essence that's the one I I wanted
关键在于——我希望它
some more definition people remember you
更清晰一些——人们记住你，是
based on how you made them feel so you
因为你让他们感受到了什么。所以你要
want to think how do I want to leave
思考，我希望
people feeling what's the emotion that I
人们在路演后有什么感受？我
want people to remember when I'm
希望人们记住的是什么情绪？是的，
pitching yeah so you want to finish the
你要以某种情绪来结束路演。你要通过
expressing um what it is that you uh
表达你想要表达的情绪或感受来结束路演，也就是
feeling that you want um you want this
你希望这个
business to be about and what's the
企业所代表的情绪或感受是什么，以及与之
opposite of that then the emotional
相反的情绪是什么。
piece so what's a pitch that is lacking
那么，什么样的路演会缺少情感部分呢？
uh well a lot of pitches finish on next
很多路演都以“下一步”结束，
steps and it's very logistical um so
而且过于注重细节。
I've seen lot of pictures that are going
我见过很多路演，一开始进展
great and then they go and then here's
顺利，然后他们开始说“
what we need to do next blah blah blah
接下来我们需要做什么”，
and then it becomes a little to-do list
然后就变成了一个待办事项清单，
and everyone goes oh that kind of landed
每个人都会说“哦”。 那样的话就有点儿
flat and if you finish on the essence
平淡无奇了，如果你最后能抓住重点，
then you actually just bring people back
实际上就能把人们带回到事情的本质，这才是关键所在。
to this is what it's really about so
所以，
that we even though we've talked about
即使我们讨论了
opportunities and next steps and the
机会、下一步、
finances and all that sort of stuff you
财务等等，你最终还是要回到我们
really about this is what we're up to in
真正关注的、我们在这个
the world I've been thinking a lot about
世界上所做的事情上。我一直在思考一些和
you know some adjacent subjects to what
我们
we're talking about here but this idea
这里讨论的主题相关的话题，比如，
that if you just asked five times more
如果你现在多问五次，
than you're currently ask asking your
你的
life would change um the secondary
生活就会改变。嗯，
example I was going to give after my
我本来想在
coffee um machine example from when I
咖啡机的例子之后再举第二个例子，那是我
was 16 was when I was 18 and I was
16岁的时候。我18岁的时候，我
completely broken that's when I was
彻底崩溃了，那时候我靠
shoplifting those Chicago Town pizzas to
偷芝加哥披萨来
feed myself and I need I start I was
养活自己。我需要启动资金，我当时正在
starting this business called wallpark
创办一家叫Wallpark的公司，
and I needed camera equipment I sent 20
我需要摄像设备。我给20家
emails to camera company saying hey I've
摄像公司发了邮件，说：“嘿，我
got um this website I'm going to launch
有一个网站要上线，
we're going to record videos on campus I
我们会在校园里录制视频，我
need some cameras if you lend us the
需要一些摄像机。如果你们借给我们
cameras we'll put your logo on all the
摄像机，我们会把你们的logo印在上面。”
videos we make on campus within 7 hours
我们在校园里拍的所有视频，三星在7小时内就把
Samsung had sent £10,000 worth of camera
价值1万英镑的摄像
equipment to my front door in my side I
设备送到我家门口了。
got an email the day after the cameras
第二天我就收到一封邮件，
arrived and it said these are um returns
说这些是退货，
send them back when you don't need them
不需要的时候就寄回去。
anymore and I'd solved someone's problem
我帮别人解决了问题，
for him because he had returned cameras
因为他把一些
in a warehouse that he didn't know what
不知道怎么
to do with he sent me £10,000 worth of
处理的退货设备扔进了仓库。三星在72小时内就免费给我寄来了价值1万英镑的
camera equipment for free within 72
摄像设备。
hours you just asked and I go oh my God
你只是提了个要求，我就想，我的天哪！
like when you're at the bottom and you
当你身处低谷，
have nothing to lose and you have an
一无所有，却又有
internet connection and a Gmail account
网络和Gmail账号的时候，
why aren't you sending out 20 30 50
为什么不每天发20、30、50封
emails a day yeah asking you think in
邮件呢？你以为是
emails I think in calls um cuz when I
邮件？我想的是打电话。因为我
was 18 you pick up the phone and make a
18岁的时候，拿起电话就打。
call um I always had this rule called
我一直有个规矩，叫“
make three calls and I remember a
打三个电话”。我记得有一次去
nightclub party that I I saw these
夜店，看到几个
15-year-olds um sitting in the street I
15岁的孩子坐在街上。我
just turned 18 and I was um loving going
刚满18岁，当时我特别喜欢去夜店。
to nightclubs and I saw these 15y olds
我去夜店的时候，看到几个十五六岁的孩子在玩
and they're skateboarding and they're
滑板，
hanging out in this little area and um
在一个小小的区域里闲逛。
they were asking me what it's like to go
他们问我去
to a nightclub and I said oh some should
夜店是什么感觉，我说，应该
put on an under 18's nightclub party so
办个未成年人夜店派对，让
that you can experience it and see what
他们体验一下，看看是什么感觉。他们说，
it's like they're like oh that would be
哦，那
amazing and and I thought oh I'm going
太棒了！我想，我要
to do it so I called the nightclub I'd
办！于是我打电话给我
been going to and said oh I have a
常去的那家夜店，说，我有个
promotions company and we run nightclub
推广公司，我们在
parties for under 18s during the school
学校假期期间会举办未成年人夜店派对，
holidays we've selected your Venue to be
我们已经选定你们的场地作为
one of our venues um for the next
我们下一个假期的场地之一，
holidays would you be interested in
你们有兴趣
discussing that he said like yeah send
讨论一下吗？他说，好啊，发
through a proposal and then I'm like oh
个方案过来吧。我说，哦，好的，我们会发的。
through a proposal and anyway we ran we
总之，我们在
ran a series of nightclub at that thing
那家夜店办了一系列派对，那是
and we it was the first time I'd ever
我第一次
made 10 grand in a night because we had
一晚上赚到一万块钱，因为有
a th people pay 10 bucks ahead and that
那么多人付了十块钱。 之前那
was a lot of money and it was all cash
笔钱很多，而且全是现金，
and uh it was it was wild and it was
呃，真是太疯狂了，我当时就只是
just literally just asking I have to say
开口问而已。我得说，
a lot of people send me messages I get
很多人给我发信息，我
um many thousands of messages a week
每周都会收到成千上万条信息，
across my inboxes LinkedIn Instagram the
来自我的收件箱、LinkedIn、Instagram、
podcast Etc and because I'm exposed to
播客等等。因为我接触到的
so many thousands of messages as I'm
信息量如此之大，我
sure you are you get to see the variance
相信你们也是如此，所以你们能够分辨出
in a good ask versus a bad ask yeah now
好的请求和糟糕的请求之间的区别。是的，现在
I want to drill down on that what are
我想深入探讨一下，
the core components of a great ask the
一个好的请求的核心要素是什么？
best ask has With or Without You energy
最好的请求应该有“有你或没有你”的能量。“有你
With or Without You energy is the energy
或没有你”的能量是指，无论有
happen with or without you so
没有你，这件事都会发生的那种能量。所以，
essentially when you say we're going to
本质上，当你说“我们要
be doing this filming and do you want to
拍摄这个项目，你想不想
send some cameras and we'll put your
送些摄像机过来，我们会把你的
logo at the bottom it's happening with
logo放在底部”时，
or without you you can be the company
无论有没有你，这件事都会发生。你可以是最终
that gets the logo or not um but it is
获得logo的公司，也可以不是，但这件事无论如何都会
happening with or without you um the
发生。最
worst asks are I desperately need this
糟糕的请求是“我迫切需要这件事
to happen and if you don't say yes yes
发生，如果你不答应，那
no one will ever say yes and and
就没人会答应，
therefore I'll give up so if I think
所以我会放弃”。 我认为
about the best asks that come through
最好的机会在于，有些事情注定
something is going to happen and it's
会发生，无论
going to happen whether I'm involved or
我是否参与，它都会发生，
not and I get to choose whether I want
而我可以选择是否参与
to jump onto that or not um and those
其中。这些
opportunities that that get pitched so
机会往往最具吸引力，也最令人兴奋。
I'll give you I'll give you an example
我举个例子：
when I first arrived in the UK I had a
我刚到英国的时候，只有一只
suitcase and a credit card and I'd never
行李箱和一张信用卡，之前从未
been above the equator I arrive in
去过赤道以北的地方。我抵达
London and I'm going to launch a
伦敦，准备在
business in London and within the first
伦敦创业。在最初的
two weeks I message all the people who
两周内，我给所有
are influential in in my industry and I
行业内有影响力的人都发了信息，
basically say I'm I'm hosting a dinner
基本上就是说，我…… 我要举办一个
party there's going to be about 30
晚宴，届时将有大约30
amazing people there who are The Who's
位
Who of the industry um I've just arrived
业内精英出席。我刚从
from Australia if you'd like to come
澳大利亚过来，如果您想
along to the dinner party let me know
参加晚宴，请告诉我，
and I'll um allocate a spot to you and
我会为您预留位置。
within two weeks I'd filled 30 spots at
两周内，我的晚宴就报满了30个名额，
my at my dinner party and they were all
而且所有受邀者都拥有
people who had massive databases the
庞大的数据库，
biggest database was like 600,000 people
最大的数据库里有大约60万人。
so so I've got this dinner party and I
所以，我举办了这个晚宴，
stand up and I say I'm Daniel Priestley
站起来说：“我是丹尼尔·普里斯特利，刚从
and I've just arrived from Australia and
澳大利亚过来，
I'm going to be launching a business
我即将在这里创办一家公司。
here I thought I'd put together a dinner
我想举办一个
party just to kind of get to know
晚宴，以便更好地认识
everyone I've got my diary with me I'd
大家。我的日程表就在手边，我很
love to make a time uh in the next
乐意在接下来的几周内抽出时间
chat with you about how we could do a
与您坐下来聊聊，探讨一下我们如何开展
commercial partnership or a joint
商业合作或
venture um as part of our launch I'll
合资，作为我们公司成立的一部分。我会过来安排
just come around and I'll make a time
时间，
and um and and and then other than that
然后……祝您一切
enjoy the evening so I walk around and I
顺利！” 那天晚上，我四处走走，
book 28 one:1 me meetings for the
安排了接下来两周的28场一对一会议。
following 2 weeks and everyone who I had
所有跟我
a one toone meeting with knew that I had
单独会面的人都知道我还有
28 other one to one meetings and they
另外28场会议，他们也
could see that I'd hosted this party
看到了我举办的那场晚宴——要知道，
mind you the party this dinner party
那场晚宴
cost like 1,500 quid it wasn't it wasn't
花了1500英镑，虽然不算便宜，
nothing but it wasn't a lot so I then
但也不算贵。之后，我就开始
end up having these uh meetings and
跟他们开会，
everyone starts agreeing to support my
大家都开始同意支持我的产品
launch so I'm pitching into existence
发布。于是我开始向大家推介，说
that we're launching this thing uh and
我们要发布这个产品。
then the biggest database with 600,000
然后，拥有60万用户的大型数据库也表示
people they say yeah we'll support your
支持。
launch so when we did the launch email
所以我们发起了产品发布邮件
campaign cign to everyone's database we
推广活动，把邮件推送给了所有人的数据库。我们
booked hundreds and hundreds and
预订了成百上千
hundreds of people we did two nights in
人的席位，在
Manchester two nights in um Birmingham
曼彻斯特和伯明翰分别举办了两晚活动，
Milton keing and then we did like three
然后
or four events in a row in London we
在伦敦连续举办了三四场活动。短短几个月，我们就靠这个实现了400
did4 million pound worth of sales off
万英镑的销售额。
it was interesting that whole experience
整个过程很有意思，就因为
of just putting together a dinner party
组织了一场晚宴。
and getting everyone involved but it had
让每个人都参与进来，但它有一种“
with or without you energy what what's
有你或没有你”的能量，这种能量
the sort of psychology underpinning that
背后的心理机制是什么？是
is it like scarcity what is it that's
稀缺性吗？是什么
causing with or Without You energy to
导致了这种“有你或没有你”的能量，
make people choose to buy from you or go
让人们选择从你这里购买或与
with you I think people like to get
你同行？我认为人们喜欢参与
involved in something that they feel is
他们认为正在
happening um and it also demonstrates
发生的事情。这也表明
that you're a key person of influence
你是一个关键的影响力人物，你
person in your industry that you have
在你的行业中确实很有影响力，你有
the confidence to say I'm I'm putting
信心说：“我正在
this on and it's going to happen we're
筹备这件事，它一定会成功。我们要
going to make the movie we're going to
拍电影，我们要
launch the business we're going to do
创业，我们要做
the thing we're going to raise the fund
这件事，我们要筹集资金。
you you're free to join or not uh
你可以自由选择加入或不加入，
totally fine uh it's there's no
完全没问题。”这其中没有任何强迫感，
neediness and humans respond to the idea
人们会对“
that they don't want to miss out on
不想错过
something that's going to happen um very
即将发生的事情”这种想法做出反应。
rarely exciting things happen right most
令人兴奋的事情很少发生，对吧？大多数时候，
of the time for most people everything's
对大多数人来说，一切都很
humdrum and then occasionally something
平淡，然后偶尔会
exciting is happening and you don't want
发生一些令人兴奋的事情，你不想
to miss out on something that's
错过。
happening so you know I don't like no
所以你知道…… 没
one likes neediness people like things
人喜欢依赖感，人们喜欢正在
that are happening and people like to
发生的事情，也喜欢
flock around key people of influence so
聚集在有影响力的关键人物周围。所以，如果你
by demonstrating that you're a key
展现出自己是一位
person of influence who's putting
有影响力的关键人物，并且正在筹划
something together people just naturally
一些事情，人们自然而然就会被你
gravitate around that it's interesting
吸引。这很有意思，让我
it reminded me of an example from a
想起了
company that uh I invested in five or
我五六年前投资的一家公司的例子。
six years ago and in one of my first
在
meetings with them I looked at their
与他们第一次会面时，我查看了他们的
website and they had this button on
网站，上面有一个按钮写着“
there that said um become a member now
立即成为会员”。
and I said we should try changing that
我说我们应该把它改成“
to join the waiting list and when I had
加入候补名单”。在我第一次
my first board meeting with this company
与这家公司召开董事会时，
they said Stephen of all the things
他们说：“斯蒂芬，
you've done for us the most valuable
你为我们做的所有事情中，最有价值的就是
thing you did was getting us to change
让我们把
that button from become member now to
那个按钮从‘立即成为会员’改成‘
join the waiting list and I said why
加入候补名单’。”我问为什么，
they said two two things happened the
他们说有两个结果：
first is the amount of inquiries we got
第一，我们收到的咨询量，也就是
the amount of people clicking that
点击那个按钮的人数，增长了
number Rose by 500% the second thing is
500%；第二，
conversion went up by about 300% because
转化率提高了大约300%。因为
previously just by changing a couple of
以前，只要改一下
words on that um button people would
按钮上的几个字，人们
click the button they would then get
点击后就会被
scheduled an appointment to have a tour
安排预约。 如果他们原本计划参观
of this um facility they would then not
这个设施，他们甚至都不会来。但当
we changed it to join the waiting list
我们把参观方式改为加入候补名单后，他们就会来，因为他们根本不重视这次参观。
and then they got an email saying hey
然后他们收到邮件说“嘿，
you've been selected for Q jump or
你已被选中参加优先参观”之类的，
whatever they would never ever miss the
他们就再也不会错过
tour and if they were late for the their
参观了。如果他们迟到
scheduled Tour by 1 hour they would
一小时，他们会
profusely text and apologize and try and
不停地发短信道歉，并试图重新
reschedule tiny shift tiny shift in just
安排时间。这可不是小事，而是一点点改变。
because if you look at how human
因为如果你了解人类
psychology works in order for someone to
心理，就会发现，一个人
want to buy something they have to be
想要购买某样东西，必须有
about 100% certain in order to join a
大约100%的把握。而加入
waiting list you only have to be 5 10%
候补名单，你只需要有5%到10%的
certain that you want to do something
把握，
and people like to warm up to things a
人们喜欢慢慢接受新事物。
little bit slowly so join the waiting
所以加入候补
list means that hey you only have to be
名单意味着，你只需要
slightly sure that you want to do this
稍微确定一下自己想做这件事，
then the uncertainty of do I get through
然后就存在着“我能不能被选中”的不确定性。
or not I've joined the waiting list I've
我已经加入了候补名单，
made a micro commitment now it's there's
做出了一个微小的承诺，现在存在着不
a an uncertainty Gap and it's like oh I
确定性的鸿沟，人们会想：“哦，我
need the certainty I need to know
需要确定性。” 我需要知道自己
whether I'm off the waiting list or I'm
是否已经从候补名单中出来，或者是否已经
through to the next phase so now we
进入下一阶段。现在我们
enter a different like oh will I will I
进入了一种不同的状态，就像“我能不能通过？”一样。
or won't I get through but it also gives
但这同时也给了
the business a great opportunity to warm
商家一个绝佳的机会来预热宣传。
people up so you talked about doing a
你刚才提到了
tour of the club let me give you some
俱乐部参观活动，那我再
other examples um glastenbury music
举几个例子。比如格拉斯伯里音乐
festival they tell people that they
节，他们会告诉人们
can't book a ticket they can only
不能直接订票，只能
register for a ticket um that they're
注册，也就是表示对
interested in a ticket so a registration
门票
of interest but not a ticket sale so
感兴趣，但不能直接购票。所以
what they do is they get 700,000 people
他们的做法是，先让70万人
to register interest and then they tell
注册，然后
you slowly who are some of the bands and
慢慢地公布一些乐队名单，让你慢慢摸清自己能不能买到票。
not and they tell you 500,000 people are
他们会告诉你，
now registered 600,000 are registered
现在已经有50万人注册了，60万人注册了，
700,000 are registered and they said but
70万人注册了，然后说，但是
there's only 4,000 tickets so then they
只有4000张票。接着他们会
say we're going to make the tickets
说，我们会在
available at 500 a.m. so only the True
早上5点开始售票，所以只有真正的
Believers are going to be there only the
铁杆粉丝才能买到票。 只有
true music fans who are willing to get
真正的乐迷愿意
up early and then there's this whole
早起，然后那种
like suspense and excitement of like
悬念和兴奋感油然而生，就像在问自己“
will I get a ticket or not people set
我能不能抢到票？”一样。人们
their alarm in the morning they know
早上就定好闹钟，因为他们知道有
that 700,000 have registered 140,000
70万人注册，只有14万人
will get through so they just fight for
能买到票，所以他们拼命抢票。
those tickets Rolex had a massive uh
劳力士在
becoming a Big Brand when they stopped
成为大品牌的过程中取得了巨大的突破，那就是他们停止直接
selling Rolexes and they started selling
销售劳力士手表，转而销售
the waiting list so you can't buy a
候补名单。所以你现在买不到
Rolex the way it works with a Rolex is
劳力士手表了。劳力士的运作方式是这样的：
you go into a Rolex retail store and the
你走进劳力士零售店，
only thing they will sell you is getting
他们唯一卖给你的就是
onto the waiting list so they won't
候补名单，他们不会
actually sell you a watch so first you
真的卖给你手表。所以你首先要
will have to get on the waiting list and
加入候补名单并
register and then about 6 months later
注册，然后大约6个月后，
they'll say good news uh we have the
他们会说：“好消息！我们有
watch that you want available but it's
你想要的那款手表了，但是
only available for 3 Days right other
只有3天的供应期。”
than that we can hold it for you for 3
除此之外，我们可以为你保留3
days but after that that we'll have to
天，之后就必须
sell it to somebody else and essentially
卖给其他人了。基本上，
everyone goes rushes down and gets the
每个人都会蜂拥而至，争相抢购。
Rolex so that cycle of join the waiting
劳力士的这种先加入等候
list and then make the sale is brilliant
名单再完成销售的循环模式非常巧妙，
and this translates perfectly for people
对于处于创业初期的人来说尤其适用。
doesn't matter whether you want to do a
无论你是想发射
rocket to Mars or whether you want to
火箭去火星，还是想开
launch a cupcake business or you want to
一家纸杯蛋糕店，或是想
do a fashion brand or you want to do uh
创立一个时尚品牌，又或是想提供
a service of bookkeeping and accounting
簿记和会计服务，
all of those you can launch a waiting
你都可以用极低的成本建立一个等候
list with minimal cost um set it up very
名单。设置起来非常
simply and basically um you use a
简单，基本上，你只
template boom you you've got a waiting
需要一个模板，就能轻松创建等候
list and you can also collect the data
名单，还能收集数据。
so you can't just join the waiting list
加入等候名单需要填写
name email answer five questions to get
姓名、邮箱，并回答五个问题：
on the waiting list how much are you
你
willing to pay what are you trying to
愿意支付多少钱？你想要
achieve what's your biggest fear of that
实现什么目标？你最担心的是什么？
could go wrong what would you try if
如果
this didn't exist so you ask a few of
没有这个产品，你会怎么做？你问了
these questions and then people get on
这些问题，人们就加入了
the waiting list you've got all that
等候名单，你就能收集到所有这些
data when people hear that they'll think
数据。人们听到这个说法时，可能会觉得
that putting someone through a set of
让别人回答一系列
sort of rigorous questions to give them
严格的问题才能获得
access to the product on the other side
产品，这会
would would deter most people but it
吓退大多数人。但这让
reminds me of a psychology study that I
我想起了一种心理学。 我
read about then wrote about in my last
读过一篇研究，后来在我的上一
book where they got two groups of people
本书里也写到了。研究里他们找了两组人，
um and it they had a boring Community
然后把一个很无聊的
Forum online as the sort of the product
在线社区论坛作为产品。他们
they let one group of people straight
让一组人直接
into the boring Community forum and then
进入这个论坛，然后
they asked them how much they
问他们
appreciated and found value in the
对这个论坛的评价和价值。
boring Community Forum that group of
这组人
people said it was boring right then
说论坛很无聊。
this study and they didn't let them into
研究里还有另一组人，他们没有直接进入
the boring Community Forum they made
论坛，而是经过了
them go through a rigorous selection
严格的
process and the people that got into the
筛选。那些最终进入论坛的人，在
when asked in surveys after how much do
调查中被问到对
you value the boring Community Forum
论坛的评价时，都说
they said it's great yeah and it's the
很棒。这其实是一种
psychological bias because you've had to
心理偏差，因为你必须努力争取才能得到它。
fight for something what you what you're
你
describing is Harvard yeah it's Harvard
描述的就像哈佛大学，没错，就是哈佛大学。它
teaches but it's hard to get in yeah um
教的都是大家一样的科目，但是很难考进去。
I use one of the other strategies for
我用来
building a business is waiting list but
拓展业务的策略之一是建立候补名单和
also discussion groups so one of the
讨论组。
things we do when we launch a business
我们创业的时候，通常会先推出
service we launch the discussion group
讨论组，而不是直接推出产品或服务。
so the first thing is um let's say let's
首先，假设
say I was going to launch a gym in
我打算在韦斯沃斯开一家健身房，
wesworth I might say we're going to do
我可能会先
discussion group on WhatsApp and we'
在WhatsApp上建一个减肥小组，然后大力
just promote the hell out of that group
推广这个小组。
and if we had 4,000 people in that group
如果小组里有4000人，
we could then launch a gym pretty easily
我们就可以很轻松地利用这个小组的影响力开办一家健身房。
off the back of the discussion group so
所以
I'm a big believer like in weight list
我非常相信，像减肥
discussion groups anything like that
小组这种
that is super fast low risk low cost
快速、低风险、低成本的方式，
these are the best ways to start
是创业的最佳途径。通过这种方式，
and you're collecting data you're
你可以收集数据，让
getting people to answer questions to
人们回答问题
get in and you're learning about what
加入，了解
the product Market fit probably is going
产品的市场契合度，确定产品是否
to be the right product for those people
真正适合韦斯沃斯的人群。
in ones worth exactly and sometimes you
有时候你会感到
get very surprised you you find out that
非常惊讶，比如你会发现，
Oh I thought that this was going to be
我原以为这个产品是为
for men who want to build big muscles
想要练出大块肌肉的男性设计的，
but it's actually for women who are
但实际上它是为
excited about CrossFit it's like oh okay
热爱CrossFit的女性设计的。你会想，哦，原来如此，我之前不
didn't didn't know that like now I've
知道。现在我
asked the questions I'm finding out that
问了这些问题，发现
it's slightly different to what I
它和我想象的略有不同。
thought I thought everyone would love
我原以为大家都会喜欢
red but everyone loves blue uh okay we
红色，但其实大家都喜欢蓝色。好吧，我们
we can we can do that so in those early
可以，我们可以做到。所以在
stages of of business you want to when I
创业初期，正如我
said uh before about conducting fast
之前所说，进行快速、
cheap experiments waiting lists
低成本的实验、建立候补名单、组织
discussion groups online assessments are
讨论小组、进行在线评估都
amazing so an online scorecard or an
非常棒。在线评分卡或
online assessment great way to think of
在线评估，可以理解为
them is a Readiness assessment so
准备度评估。
Readiness assessment like are you ready
准备度评估就像是：你准备好
to launch a podcast answer 10 questions
推出播客了吗？回答10个问题
to find out are you ready to build your
即可了解；你准备好打造
brand answer 10 questions to find out
品牌了吗？回答10个问题即可了解；
are you ready to be an investor in this
你准备好投资这类
type of investment answer 10 questions
项目了吗？回答10个问题即可
to find out so it's an online assessment
了解。这是一个在线评估，
where you answer a series of questions
你需要回答一系列问题
to get a Readiness score and then based
来获得准备度分数。然后，根据这个
on the Readiness score uh you people
分数，你
will then find out if they're 30% ready
可以知道自己的准备度是30%还是
40% ready and people love these
40%。人们喜欢这种
Readiness scores this is one of the
准备度分数，这是
fastest ways to test an idea and getting
测试想法和获取兴趣信号的最快方法之一。
Downstream from lead generation in
在
business so you essentially have to
商业中，一切都是潜在客户开发的下游环节。所以，你基本上必须先
uh you have to generate leads and then
开发潜在客户，然后再
you figure out if you've got a business
确定你是否拥有一个商业项目。
or not so the fastest you can get into
因此，你能以最快的速度进入…… 潜在客户开发至关重要。
the worst things that people do when
人们
they're starting a business is that they
创业时最常犯的错误之一就是
think that having a business is about
认为创业就是关注供应
the supply side of what they're doing
端。
supply side means your ability to look
供应端指的是你服务客户、让
after a customer and keep a customer
客户
happy but actually a business has to
满意的能力，但实际上，创业必须
start with the demand side it's you've
从需求端开始。你
got to test the demand side before you
必须先测试需求端，才能
test the supply side if you can't
测试供应端。如果你无法
manufacture demand there's no point
创造需求，那么
manufacturing Supply it doesn't matter
制造供应端就毫无意义。
you know if you say oh I you I've come
比如说，你
up with this chili and basil flavored
研发出了辣椒罗勒口味的
ice cream great you can make that but
冰淇淋，很好，你可以生产，但
does anyone want that right you got to
有人想要吗？你必须
check out whether you have the ability
检验自己是否有能力将
to to get that um product into a market
产品推向市场。
so what I see so many people they take
我看到很多人会考取
qualifications they get certifications
资格证书，获得认证，筹集资金，租用场地，
a venue they might book an office they
预订办公室，
might buy laptop computers all of this
购买笔记本电脑等等，他们可能会
stuff and they might spend SP 3 to 6
花费三到
months doing that and then finally after
六个月的时间去做这些，最终却
all of that they then experience oh no
发现根本没
one's interested in this now what do I
人对这个感兴趣。现在，我该如何处理这些投入呢？ 举
ice cream example what should they have
个例子，他们应该怎么
done join the waiting list we're
做？加入等候名单！我们即将
launching Chile and bzel ice cream if
推出辣椒巴塞尔冰淇淋，如果
you'd like to try it and taste it join
您想尝尝鲜，就加入
the waiting list people don't know what
等候名单吧。不过，人们不知道
they want though because in the ice
自己想要什么，因为
cream example it's a taste thing right
冰淇淋只是口味问题，对吧？
so it sounds good but in reality it
听起来不错，但实际上
could be re like so I mean this is a
可能……我的意思是，这
crazy idea it's a terrible idea that
想法很疯狂，甚至很糟糕，但
we're but but anyway let's let's go with
不管怎样，我们先试试看。
it um so you you create a waiting list
所以，你创建一个等候名单，我们会
where we're doing really wild flavored
推出各种
ice creams and it's crazy flavors like
口味独特的冰淇淋，比如
chili and Basel ice cream and salt and
辣椒巴塞尔冰淇淋、盐和
pepper ice cream and blah blah blah if
胡椒冰淇淋等等。如果
you're interested in really different
您对各种
exciting new flavors of ice cream join
新奇刺激的冰淇淋口味感兴趣，就加入
the waiting list and we will invite you
等候名单吧。我们会邀请您
to a taste tester um when it's ready
参加试吃活动。等冰淇淋上市后，
you'll get to come to an exclusive event
您将有机会参加一个专属活动，
recipes in in central London so now you
在伦敦市中心品尝我们最新的配方。现在，你要
promote the waiting list and you see can
宣传等候名单，看看能不能
I get lots of people and some of the
吸引很多人。一些
questions might be which flavor are you
问题可能是：你
most looking forward to are you looking
最期待哪种口味？你最
forward to octop octopus ice cream are
期待…… 章鱼冰淇淋，
you looking forward to you know which
你期待的是哪
one right so you go through and you they
一款呢？对吧？让他们
answer all the questions and then they
回答所有问题，然后
join the waiting list then you say join
加入等候名单。接着，你邀请他们加入
the ice cream Discovery discussion group
冰淇淋探索讨论组。这样，
right so now they're in there talking
他们就可以在群里讨论
about their favorite ice creams and what
自己最喜欢的冰淇淋口味，以及
crazy flavors they like and you can
他们喜欢的各种奇葩口味。你还可以
actually have a daily poll and you're
每天发起投票，
doing that all in WhatsApp and then you
所有这些都在WhatsApp上进行。然后，你可以邀请他们参加
say now come to the the event that we've
我们的试吃活动，还
got the taste testing event you could
可以
launch the ice cream assess
发起冰淇淋测评。
are you are you the Savory ice cream
你是哪种类型的冰淇淋爱好者？是咸味冰淇淋
person or the sweet ice cream are you
爱好者还是甜味冰淇淋爱好者？
the you know so you could have four ice
你可以邀请四位
cream personalities and they take the
冰淇淋性格
test and find out which ice cream
测试者，让他们测试自己的
personality they have so you can do all
性格类型。所有
of this stuff for free or almost for
这些活动几乎都是免费的，甚至不用你亲手
free without making a scoop of ice cream
制作一勺冰淇淋。所有
right none of this stuff involves
这些活动都不需要
actually any commercial kitchens none of
商业厨房，也不
it involves packaging or branding or any
需要包装、品牌推广或其他任何
of the expensive stuff you're just doing
昂贵的投入。你只是在
the things that's testing whether people
测试人们是否真的
are actually interested in this and if
对此感兴趣，以及是否
it's crickets if you put a lot of effort
投入大量精力却无人问津。
into trying to get people interested in
为了让大家对
this and you've got 12 people in your
这个感兴趣，你的小组只有12个人，
little group and they're all you know
他们却面面相觑，
sadly looking at each other going
无奈地问：“
where's the basil ice cream you know
罗勒冰淇淋在哪儿？” 你知道，
this is never going to fly if it you
这肯定行不通。
know I was thinking there some people
我想，也许有些人会来参加
might come to the discussion group you
讨论小组，比如
know your friends whatever your mom
你的朋友，或者你妈妈，
comes down she goes yeah your ice
她下来后会说：“丹尼尔，你的
cream's great Daniel well you want to do
冰淇淋真棒！” 你想做“
cold Outreach cold Outreach I don't know
冷门推广”吗？我不知道
how long we're going to talk about ice
我们还要聊多久
creams but cold Outreach is is where you
冰淇淋，但“冷门推广”的
essentially make um a list of all the
本质就是列出所有
communities and groups that exist online
在线社区和小组，
all the all the accounts that already
所有已经
have followers and you just cold
拥有粉丝的账号，然后你就可以“冷门
Outreach a thousand people and and get
推广”一千个人，让
them involved but Daniel what if someone
他们参与进来。但是丹尼尔，如果有人
steals my
偷了我的
idea well my my experience tells me
想法怎么办？我的经验告诉我，
until you've got a Ferrari no one steals
除非你拥有一辆法拉利，否则没人会偷
your idea yeah people steal ideas from
你的想法。没错，人们会偷那些
people who have Ferraris right so it's
拥有法拉利的人的想法，对吧？这就是
that bias towards if you've been
偏见，如果你
successful in the past then your ideas
过去成功了，你的想法
are worth stealing the beauty of having
就值得被偷。一无所有的好处是，
nothing is no one's going to steal your
没有人会偷你的
ideas ever they're going to look at your
想法，他们只会关注…… 你
account on Instagram and go oh you got
在Instagram上注册了账号，然后心想：哦，你一个
no followers and you know you haven't
粉丝都没有，而且你也
got a Ferrari so I'm not going to steal
没有法拉利，所以我不会窃取
your idea so you've got this great
你的创意。
Advantage when you're starting from zero
当你从零开始的时候，你拥有一个巨大的优势：
that no one no one will steal the idea
没有人会窃取你的创意。还有一点，
and here's the other thing ideas aren't
创意本身并不
worth anything uh here's a great idea
值钱。比如说，有个绝妙的主意：
let's rip down all the old buildings in
我们把伦敦所有的旧建筑都拆掉，
London and build brand new buildings
然后建造全新的建筑。
what's that idea worth trillions well it
这个想法值几万亿？
would be worth trillions if we did that
如果我们真的这么做了，它的确会值几万亿。但
well actually no the value is for the
实际上，价值在于
person who does it so if someone else
执行它的人。所以，如果有人
steals your idea does it they deserve
窃取了你的创意，那就
the money right let them have it they're
让他们拿走吧，他们理应得到这笔钱。他们
better at executing get on with the next
执行力更强，然后继续下一个创意，
idea and be better at executing next
争取下次做得更好。
time so if someone's able to execute
所以，如果有人
better and faster than you they deserve
比你执行得更好更快，他们理应得到
that money that's fine let them have it
这笔钱，没问题，让他们
get on to the next idea thinking about
拿走吧，然后继续下一个创意。想想
it like this podcast there's lots of
这个播客，现在有很多
there's like three million podcasts a
播客，大概有三百万个，
lot of podcast the idea itself to start
很多播客。播
a podcast isn't where the value is
客的价值并不在于创意本身，
pitching and um and also the commercials
而在于推销。 还有
behind the scenes you know creating the
幕后的商业运作，你知道，就是创造
right offers making sales so this is the
合适的优惠，促成销售。这是
other other thing that early stage
初创
businesses need to do you got to stop
企业需要做的另一件事：你必须停止
calling yourself an entrepreneur and
称自己为企业家，而
start calling yourself a salesp person
要称自己为销售人员。在创业初期，
you're going to get out there and make
你必须走出去，努力
sales in the early days so a lot of
销售。很多
people are really uncomfortable with the
人对
idea of making sales but that's what an
销售这个概念感到很不自在，但这正是企业家的工作。
entrepreneur does an entrepreneur is a
企业家就是
salesperson especially in those first
销售人员，尤其是在最初的
couple of years you you are the chief
几年里，你就是首席
salesperson if you can't sell it
销售员。如果你卖不出去，
nobody's going to sell it I've the heard
就没人能卖出去。我听说过
of a lot of these topics is this idea of
很多关于失败的话题，
failure because you're talking about
因为我们谈到了
experimentation we're talking about ask
实验，谈到了尝试。
with all these things and people's
人们对待
relationship with failure seems to
失败的态度似乎
correlate to their eventual success over
与他们最终的成功密切相关。尤其是在
the last couple of years in particular
过去几年里，
especially from doing this podcast and a
通过制作这个播客以及
I run I've realized that that
我运营的许多其他企业，我意识到，那种
experimental mindset the type of person
实验性的思维方式——那种能够
that quickly runs the test versus sits
迅速进行测试
and procrastinates for years is really
而不是坐等多年拖延的人——才是
the winner in most Pursuits and then I
大多数成功者。然后我
studied Amazon and Jeff bezos's
研究了亚马逊，杰夫·贝佐斯在
shareholder letter says this has to be
致股东的信中也提到了这一点。
the best place in the world to fail I
世界上最适合失败的地方。我
looked at booking.com and they have that
研究了Booking.com，
moment where they launched their
他们推出
experimentation platform because they
实验平台的那一刻，是因为他们
were sick of arguing about what the best
厌倦了
feature was in the boardroom I look at
在董事会里争论哪个功能最好。我又想起
Thomas Watson back in I think 1950 or 60
托马斯·沃森，大概在1950或1960年，
where he says um one of his employees
他说他的一名员工犯了
had just made a huge mistake which cost
一个大错，给
the company
公司造成了
$600,000 and he's asked in an interview
60万美元的损失。在一次采访中，有人问他是否会
are you going to fire them and he goes
解雇他，他回答说：“
fire them I just spent $600,000 training
解雇他，我刚花了60万美元培训
them these people seem to have a
他。”这些人似乎
different attitude towards the value of
对失败的价值有着不同的态度。是的，
failure yeah this goes back to the
这可以追溯到
school system the school system is
学校教育体系。学校教育体系是
designed for component labor and you
为组件式劳动设计的，而你
don't want components to fail um what
不希望组件出现故障。
we're doing now is different so we're
我们现在的情况不同了，
especially now we're entering entering
尤其是我们正在进入
the age of AI so in in a post AI world
人工智能时代。在后人工智能时代，
most of the things that we think of as
我们认为
valuable that the school system could
学校教育体系
possibly teach us are not going to be
可能教给我们的那些有价值的东西，将不再那么
very valuable very long so functionality
有价值。功能性
versus Vitality when something is
与重要性：功能性
functional it performs a task reliably
是指可靠地执行任务，而重要性是指不可靠、不值得依赖。
Irreplaceable life force energy so what
可注入的生命力能量，所以
we have to do is recognize that the
我们必须认识到，
value has swung from something that is
价值已经从
reliably able to perform a task to
可靠地执行任务转变为为
energy into into a project so I know
项目注入生命力能量。我知道
this is kind of woooo but essentially
这听起来有点玄乎，但本质上，
this is the difference when you are
这就是区别：当你为
something you're okay with failure we're
某物注入生命力能量时，你可以接受失败；
we're just conducting experiments we're
我们只是在进行实验，
finding the way that works and we just
寻找有效的方法，我们可能已经
found 900 ways that don't work and now
找到了900种行不通的方法，现在
we're going to find the next one and you
我们要寻找下一个。而
you're bringing something into existence
你创造某物，就像
it's just like being a parent you know
为人父母一样，你知道，当
when when you see the child P down you
你看到孩子摔倒时，
you get the child back up and you get
你会扶起他，让他继续
them onto the next thing and when we
做下一件事。当我们
learn riding a bike we have to go
学习骑自行车时，我们也必须经历从
through falling off the bike so there's
自行车上摔下来。
all of these experiences that you know
所有这些经历都让你体会到为
energy to something and that involves a
某物注入生命力能量是什么感觉，这其中包含着
process of failure um and then
失败的过程。
functionality if we're really um putting
如果我们真的把
our value around the idea that something
价值建立在“某物必须
has to be functional or that I have to
实用”或“我必须
be functional that my value is in my
实用”的概念上，认为我的价值在于我的
functionality then failure is such a bad
实用性，那么失败就成了……
thing so this is a big difference in how
坏事，所以
the pendulum is now swinging we have to
现在钟摆的摆动方向发生了很大的变化。我们必须
remove the idea that you are valuable
摒弃“你之所以有价值是
because you're reliably functional we
因为你可靠且功能齐全”这种观念，我们
have to swing it back to this idea that
必须把它摆回到“
you're valuable because you breathe life
你之所以有价值是因为你为某物注入了生命
force energy into something for someone
能量”这种观念上。对于
that doesn't know the definition of Life
不了解生命
Force energy how would you define that
能量定义的人来说，你会如何定义它呢？“
so this word Vitality has two
活力”这个词有两个
definitions Irreplaceable and life force
定义：不可替代和生命力。
so if something is vital it's
所以，如果某物至关重要，它就是
Irreplaceable and it's life force so you
不可替代的，也是生命力。你
need to find something that you are the
需要找到某种东西，你就是那
Irreplaceable life force you pitch it
不可替代的生命力，你把它
into existence you create it you
创造出来，你
innovate it um you take ownership of it
创新它，你拥有它，
you enroll others into it um that's the
你让其他人参与其中。这就是
alignment kind of thing you're talking
你所说的“契合”状态。
about you're aligned to that thing yeah
你与那件事物契合，是的，
you fully expressed your life you're
你充分展现了你的生命，
enjo you're enjoying this because it's
你享受它，因为这是
your life Journey um and uh you know
你的人生旅程。你知道，
we're so tuned out from from the idea of
我们对这个概念如此麻木，以至于
this that that essentially we have to
我们基本上必须
relearn what the hell does this even
重新学习它到底是什么意思。
mean this definition life force energy
生命能量的定义
is what kids do right think about you
是小孩子才会做的事，对吧？ 想象一下，
know everyone's talking and everyone's
大家都在认真地交谈，气氛很
serious and then a 5-year-old bounces
严肃，这时一个五岁的小孩蹦蹦跳跳地
into the room look what I found right
跑进房间，大喊：“看！我发现了什么！”然后大家就都惊呆了，哇！
like whoa and suddenly everyone's
突然间，所有人都被
disrupted and they bring energy into the
打断了。他们给
house they bring energy into a room so
房子带来了活力，给房间带来了活力，所以
they just know what it's like to fully
他们知道如何充分
Express themselves and breathe life
表达自己，如何将
force energy into something let me give
生命力注入事物。我再举个
example they're
例子，他们是
magicians and they have these like fake
魔术师，他们戴着假
thumbs and these things those fake
拇指之类的东西。这些假
thumbs are functional things right
拇指是实用的，对吧？
there's a functional thing called a fake
假拇指确实是一种实用工具，可以用来表演
thumb and that's how you do the magic
魔术。
trick but it doesn't mean that everyone
但这并不意味着每个戴
who has that fake thumb can do the magic
假拇指的人都能表演魔术。
trick in fact some people do the magic
事实上，有些人表演魔术时，
trick and people go you're just wearing
人们会说：“你只是戴了
a fake thumb right then there are
个假拇指而已。”而有些
magicians who completely make you
魔术师却能让你完全
believe in the magic and they're using
相信他们的魔术，他们也只是戴着
just the fake thumb as well they're just
假拇指而已，他们和其他魔术师一样，只是
doing the same functional thing as the
用了同样的功能性工具，
other magician but they're so good at
但他们技艺高超，
doing it they're so good at enrolling
他们非常擅长让
you in it they're so good at getting you
你信服。 他们非常擅长吸引你的
your attention and your engagement and
注意力，让你参与其中，并让你的
your beliefs align to what they want you
信念与他们想要你
to believe that suddenly bringing that
相信的保持一致。突然间，
magic trick to life is what the magician
魔术师仿佛变魔术一般，将魔法变为现实。
is doing when you study magicians you
当你研究魔术师时，你会
realize that it's not about the gadgets
发现，关键不在于道具，不在于
it's not about the functionality it's
功能，而在于
about the way they do the trick it's the
他们表演魔术的方式，在于
way they breathe the life force into the
他们如何赋予魔术生命力。生命力
trick so the the life force is the magic
就是魔法，是
it's the way you it's the way you bring
你赋予它
it to life so the idea that I noticed
生命的方式。
years ago when I wrote the book key
多年前，我在写《关键
person of influence was that there are
影响力人物》这本书时注意到，有些人能够让
around them um and the these people they
周围的事物发生改变。这些人
build reputation their names come up in
建立声誉，他们的名字成为人们
conversation they have more fun they
谈论的话题，他们更有乐趣，他们
build reputation all that sort stuff
建立声誉等等，事情就会发生。
happens and when they're involved in
当他们参与
something it all comes to life and when
某件事时，一切都会运转起来；而当
they're not involved in it it almost
他们不参与时，事情几乎就会
dissipates it get something magically
消散，神奇的事情也
doesn't happen um your involvement in 40
不会发生。比如，你参与了40家
different country uh companies people
不同国家的公司，人们
would ask the question but how are you
会问，你怎么能
involved in 40 different companies and
参与40家不同的公司？
the thing is that you're not
关键在于，你并非在
functionally involved in 40 different
功能上参与其中。 你参与了40家不同的
companies but you're breathing a life
公司，但你也为这
force energy into 40 different companies
40家公司注入了生命能量。
there's something that your your energy
你的能量
brings that stuff happens with you
带来了一些东西，你
involved that wouldn't happen if you
参与其中，就会发生一些如果你
weren't involved you're the IRL life
不参与就不会发生的事情。你是现实生活中的
force and if that Irreplaceable life
生命力，如果这种不可替代的生命力
force comes gets gets removed the result
消失，结果就会
won't be the same if you're involved the
不一样。如果你参与其中，
result will be different and that's what
结果就会不同。这就是
people want from you and it's not
人们对你的期望，而不是仅仅提供工作能力。
functionality no one's saying can you
没人会问你能不能
come and work in the office it's very
来办公室上班。这非常非常
very interesting very very true and I
有趣，非常真实。由此引出了
the two sub questions that spiraled off
两个子问题：
that were how does one know and does one
一个人如何知道，以及是否
need to know what their Vitality their
需要知道自己的活力，也就是
life force energy is do we need to know
生命能量是什么？我们需要知道吗？有
and is there a way for us to find out
没有办法找到它？
what it is we need to get into
我们需要进入一个可以
environments where it becomes normal to
正常
explore this stuff and we need to be
探索这些概念的环境，我们需要和充满
around people who are full of life so
活力的人在一起。
when you are around vital people you
当你和充满活力的人在一起时，你会
discover things about your own Vitality
发现自己活力的某些方面。
you've had this experience of launching
你曾有过推出
a podcast that gives you access to the
播客的经历，让你有机会接触到
world's most interesting people and me
世界上最有趣的人，而我……
um and you've got this uh I bet from
我相信，你从
every single person you've raised your
每一个与你互动的人身上都能提升
energy you've raised Your vitality
能量，提升活力。
something inside you was awoken in each
每一次互动都唤醒了你内在的某种东西，
interaction that lifted your vibration
提升了你的振动频率。
up when you're in a low vibration
当你身处一个低频振动的
environment where everyone's functional
环境中，
everyone is suppressing their life force
每个人都为了维持运转而压抑自己的生命力时，
in order to be functional you
你
essentially just resonate with that and
基本上也会受到这种环境的影响，
you suppress your life force in order to
为了维持运转而压抑自己的生命力。
be functional so we need to get into
所以我们需要进入一个以
environments where Vitality is the norm
活力为常态的环境，在那里
uh where we raise our energy where we
我们可以提升能量，可以
feel good about thinking about vision
愉快地思考愿景、
mission and values and we feel good
使命和价值观，可以愉快地
about exploring origin and what what
探索起源以及它
value that might add to the world um it
可能为世界带来的价值。
feels normal to be conducting experiment
进行实验会感觉很
it feels normal to be making sales um it
自然，销售会感觉很自然，
feels normal to want to be a key person
想要成为行业关键人物会感觉很自然，
feels normal to have a conversation
讨论
the planet and how they could be used
地球上已有的资源以及如何以不同的方式利用它们会感觉很自然。
differently so all of those things
所有这些都
happen inside the right environment so I
发生在合适的环境中。我常
have a saying that environment dictates
说，环境决定
performance I went into a number of
表现。我曾
Prisons with a charity called key for
与一个名为“生命之钥”（Key for Life）的慈善机构一起走访过一些监狱，
life and what we discovered is that a
我们发现
lot of these young men are entrepreneurs
很多年轻人…… 男人都是企业家，
but in their environment the product
但在他们所处的环境中，
that you would sell is an illegal
他们想卖的产品却是非法
product but there in that environment
产品。在那种环境下，
the only successful entrepreneurs they
他们
come across and the only successful
遇到的唯一成功的
entrepreneurs they meet are selling
企业家都是
drugs so they go oh that is my pathway
贩毒的，于是他们就想，哦，这就是我的道路，这就是
that's what I do that's my mentoring
我该做的，这就是我的导师，
that's the environment if you were to
这就是环境。如果你把
take these same entrepreneurial spirit
这些年轻人的创业精神拿出来，
that these young men have and showed
给
them oh here's an IT services company
他们看一家IT服务公司，
they'd go start an IT services company
他们就会去创办一家IT服务公司；
or here's a book publishing business oh
或者给他们看一家图书出版公司，他们就会想，哦，好吧，
okay now I'm going to be a book
现在我要成为一名图书
publisher so these their entrepreneurial
出版商。这就是他们的创业
Spirit the only place they saw in the
精神。在他们所处的环境中，唯一能看到
environment of someone who's on the rise
成功案例的
was this drug dealer friend so they got
就是那个贩毒的朋友，所以他们也
involved in it so environment dictates
跟着做了。所以，环境决定表现。
performance what we need to do is we
我们需要做的就是
need to find environments that lift us
找到能够提升我们的环境。
up what if we're not in an environment
如果我们身处的环境无法
that lifts us up because there's going
提升我们呢？因为
now that are that when you've described
现在就有几百万人处于这种状态。当你描述了
the definition of Life Force energy and
生命能量的定义，并且
you've also used the word stagnation as
用“停滞”这个词
almost the antithesis of that they're
几乎作为它的反义词时，他们会怎么想呢？
thinking oh my God I would love some
我的天哪，我太需要一些
life force energy I'm in a corporate job
生命能量了！我在城里一家公司上班，已经干了
years I'm I'm
十年了。我感觉自己像
institutionalized in this place because
被困在这个地方一样，因为在
I've been here so long that I don't even
这里待的时间太长了，我甚至不
know what the outside world would look
知道外面的世界是什么样子。
like and I've got these ideas but I've
我有一些想法，但我
been they can feel their soul has been
感觉他们的灵魂在
drained to some
某种程度上被抽干了。我背负着
degree got a mortgage change well change
房贷，每周
environments for at least an hour or two
至少要换个环境一两个小时。
a week and what I mean by that is I'll
我的意思是，我
give you an example when I was 21 I was
举个例子，我21岁的时候，经常
going out to pubs drinking with friends
和朋友们去酒吧喝酒，
all the time we're getting drunk and
我们喝得烂醉，
that was the normal night and there was
那是我们平常的夜晚。有
this one night where these people turned
一天晚上，来了一群
up who did laop uh Latin Jive dancing
跳拉丁摇摆舞的人，
and I looked across the room and I saw
我环顾四周，看到
them Jive dancing and I went oh that's
他们在跳摇摆舞，心想：哇，
incredible and I get talking to the the
太棒了！我和其中一个
guy and I say how did you how do you do
人聊了起来，问他：“你们是怎么做到的？你们是怎么做到的？”当时有
this and there's like six beautiful
六个漂亮的
girls and this one or two guys who
女孩和一两个男孩，
they're all waiting for a spin and I'm
他们都在等着轮流跳。我问他们：“你们
like how do how are you doing this he
好吗？” 他这么做之后
goes come to dance classes so I'm like
就去上舞蹈课了，所以我就想，
go to dance classes that's I would never
去上舞蹈课吧，我以前从来没去过
go to dance classes I rock up at dance
舞蹈课。结果我去了舞蹈
class and then when I was there I was in
课，到了那里之后，我发现
this environment where it was completely
那里的环境里
normal to dance that was just the normal
跳舞完全正常，
thing in that environment you grab a
在那种环境下跳舞就是理所当然的事。你找个
partner and you the music comes on and
舞伴，音乐响起，
they show you the moves and you do the
老师会教你动作，你就跟着做。
moves when they demoed the moves and I
我
can vividly remember this from 20 years
清楚地记得20年前
ago when they demoed the moves I thought
他们教动作的时候，我心想，
to myself there is no way I'll learn
我不可能
that in 3 months and then by the end of
在3个月内学会这些。结果
that first 2hour session I'm doing the
第一个2小时的课结束时，我已经能跳
whole routine and I'm comfortable with
整套动作了，而且跳得很流畅。
it I'm like wow I can do this so being
我当时就想，哇，我居然能做到！所以，
in the you can't do it outside of the
你不可能脱离
environment you can only do it in the
环境就做到，你只能在那种
environment so entrepreneurship is an
环境下做到。创业也是一种
environment thing you you do it inside
环境，你必须在特定的环境中进行，
do that outside of the environment so
脱离环境很难做到。所以
you basically have to find entrepreneur
你基本上需要找到创业者
meetups entrepreneur groups um you you
聚会、创业者团体，你需要
find a mentor uh you you know in every
找到导师，你知道，
city around the world right now there
现在世界各地每个城市都有
are entrepreneur meetups every night of
创业者聚会。
the week uh online there are
一周七天，每天晚上都有线上
entrepreneurial events every day of the
创业活动，
week so you just get in you just get in
所以你只要加入进去，融入那种
the environment there's this thing
氛围就行了。有一种说法
called social shedding which I've never
叫“社交脱节”，我
actually shared with anybody before but
以前从来没跟任何人说过。
it's this idea that when you take that
它的意思是，当你迈出
first step into dance class and you get
第一步走进舞蹈教室，
to see behind the curtain of another
看到另一个
world you slowly no longer resonate with
世界的帷幕后，你会慢慢地和
your other friendship group and what and
你的其他朋友群体产生隔阂。这之间
there's often a friction there where
常常会产生摩擦，
they say oh Dan you Dan's D they start
他们会说：“哦，丹，你是丹，你跳的是D舞。”然后开始
cracking the jokes oh Dan's a ballet
开玩笑说：“哦，丹是芭蕾舞演员，
dance and now Lads and what they're
现在跳的是哥们儿舞。”他们这么做其实和“
this phrase misery loves company they
同病相怜”这句话有点关系。他们
don't want you to leave no one wants you
不想让你离开，没人想让你
to change you're Dan Priestly we know
改变。“你是丹·普里斯特利，我们认识的
you as this do not change your identity
你就是这样的你。不要改变你的身份。
if you try to change your identity we
如果你试图改变，我们
will mock you we will disguised as a
会嘲笑你，我们会用一种讽刺的方式来嘲弄你，我们会
roast and we will try and hold you back
想方设法阻止你。
because if you change what does that say
因为如果你改变了，那说明
about us what that's that's holding a
我们什么？这就像一面镜子，照着镜子里的自己，
mirror up to me it means that I'm less
意味着我
than you in some way and I hear this
在某些方面不如你。” 经常听到
from entrepreneurs or startup
创业者或初创
entrepreneurs that when they that
企业主说，当他们
decision to start building a personal
决定打造个人
brand or starting that cupcake business
品牌或开办纸杯蛋糕店时，
typically causes resistance from their
通常会遭到
existing Social Circle and then this
现有社交圈的抵制。然后，
decision whether they want to socially
他们会面临是否要“脱离”社交圈的抉择，
shed which means letting some of those
这意味着要放弃一些
people
人。
go if we were born at any other time in
如果我们出生在历史上的其他任何时期，
history you would grow up in a town get
你会在一个小镇长大，在那里
a job in that local Town go to school in
工作，在那里上学，
that local Town um and everything would
一切都
revolve around just the local issues of
围绕着当地的事务。
of that particular place you probably
你可能
entire lifetime and you'd have this very
一辈子只认识一千个人，你的社交
tight Circle there's something in our
圈子非常小。在我们的
Evolution about being part of these
进化过程中，融入这些
little local communities and for the
小型本地社区似乎是一种必然。而现在，
first time in history you can choose to
历史上第一次，你可以选择
be tapped into a global Community anyone
加入全球社区。
in the world who who shares values or
世界上任何与你价值观相同或
you want to share their values it's now
你想分享价值观的人，现在都可以
freely available to to us there's
自由地加入。这
something that feels very foreign about
感觉很陌生，
that because it's never happened for the
因为在
last 5,000 years and then there's
过去的五千年里从未发生过。但同时，这也很令人
something very exciting about this where
兴奋，你会意识到，
you go actually I'm living in a
我生活在一个
different time now this is an incredible
不同的时代，这是一个不可思议的
moment I think that what's happening is
时刻。我认为，我们正在经历的是…… 我们正经历着
that we're going through an Empire shift
一场帝国式的转变，
and the current Empire shift is this
而当前的帝国式转变正是
Empire shift away from geography to
从地域性向
digital which means that we connect on
数字化的转变，这意味着我们
values and we connect on purpose and we
基于价值观、目标、起源、
connect on Origin Mission Vision and
使命、愿景等等进行连接。
those sorts of things so what the larger
因此，更大的
shift that that's actually happening is
转变在于：
this shift of do I want to play by the
我是否愿意遵循
old rules of the geographical based
基于地域的旧规则，
system or do I want to play by the new
还是愿意遵循
rules of being in the cloud and in the
云端的新规则？在
cloud anything is possible because I can
云端，一切皆有可能，因为我可以
go anywhere I can do anything I can
去任何地方，做任何事情，
access any information I can connect
获取任何信息，
with any person on the planet and as
与地球上的任何人联系。
soon as you make this shift into the new
一旦你完成了向新
Empire that's where everything starts to
帝国的转变，一切都将开始
shift and now you so we all have to make
改变。现在，我们都必须做出
that shift so the big shift is not even
这种转变。所以，真正的转变不仅仅是
just changing your friendship group it's
改变你的朋友圈，而是拥有拥抱新帝国的
the courage to Empire it's the courage
勇气，是敢于
to say actually you know what the world
承认世界已经与
is a very different place than what I
我出生时截然不同的勇气。世界正在经历
big change the faster I can actually get
巨大的变革，我越快
into this wave and surf this wave the
融入这股浪潮，驾驭它，就
better that's so interesting and one of
越好。这真是太有趣了！
those shifts from the old Empire to the
从旧帝国到
new Empire is seen in building a
新帝国的转变之一体现在
personal brand because the old
个人品牌的构建上。 过去，
Gatekeepers of media and reputation were
媒体和声誉的把关人
just newspapers and the radio and there
只有报纸和广播，而且这类媒体也就
was like you know 10 of those so you got
十来家，所以你能
to be lucky to get on one of those now
上其中一家就得靠运气。现在，
in the new Empire in the clouds you can
在云端的新帝国里，你可以
build your own Media company around you
围绕自身打造专属的媒体公司，
per Mission free you can digitize your
每个项目都是免费的。你可以将你的
value um you can connect with anyone in
价值数字化，并与世界上任何认同你理念的人建立联系。
that you do so when we launched the most
所以，当我们推出
recent business um score app we launched
最新的商业应用——Score App时，我们最初
it in London but because it was the
在伦敦发布，但由于
pandemic um we ended up with employees
疫情的影响，我们的员工遍布
all over the world and we've never had
全球。我们从未设立过
an office and we still don't have an
办公室，现在也依然如此。
office and it's this incredible business
这是一个不可思议的商业模式。
and what's happening is that we now have
现在，
clients signing up every single day over
每天都有超过
100 people sign up and we have clients
100位新客户注册，我们的客户
in 152 countries I checked yesterday and
遍布152个国家（我昨天查过）。
they resonate with a message and there's
他们都认同我们的理念。这家
no the business doesn't exist anywhere
公司并不存在
there's no actual place that you can go
实体办公场所，你无法亲自
to visit score app it's just a digital
前往体验Score App。它只是一个数字
business the employees are everywhere
企业，员工遍布全球，
the customers are everywhere but what
客户也遍布全球。但真正
holds it together are these intangible
维系这一切的，是那些无形的
things such as values and vision and the
东西，比如价值观。 愿景、
value that we offer and the ideas and
我们提供的价值、理念，以及
the you know all the stories and all of
所有那些故事和所有
that intangible stuff now exists in the
无形的东西，现在都存在于
cloud and the whole business exists in
云端，整个业务也存在于
the cloud so it is an incredible time
云端，所以这是一个不可思议的
time personal brand is one of these
时代。个人品牌就是这样一种
incredible things where you don't need
不可思议的东西，你不需要任何
permission you can just go straight to
许可，就可以直接进入
the market you've done that um and
市场。你已经做到了。
anyone who resonates with your story
任何与你的故事、
your ideas you know your the things that
理念、
you want to get done in the world they
你想要在世界上完成的事情产生共鸣的人，都
can just follow along um I I hate the
可以跟随你。我讨厌把
idea of personal brand being like
个人品牌想象成
showing up and doing
露面
dances it's actually it's about sending
跳舞，它实际上是在
out a signal of this is what I'm up to
发出一个信号：这就是我
in the world and do you want to come
在世界上正在做的事情，你想加入吗？
along for the ride do you want to be
你想成为其中的
part of that like are you up for this
一部分吗？你
game that I'm playing do you want to do
想参与我正在玩的游戏吗？
you want to take part in what I'm
你想参与我
interested in so it's it's a connection
感兴趣的事情吗？所以它是一种连接，
it's it's not an image it's not like a
它不是一个形象，也不是一个反复重复的
voice or a a message that gets repeated
声音或信息，而是“
over and over it's I'm up to something
我
in the world and I would love more
在世界上做一些事情，我希望更多”。 想
people to be part of that come with me I
成为其中一员的人，请跟我来。我
think um I Heard Adam Grant speak in one
想，嗯，我听亚当·格兰特在
of his books about the big misconception
他的一本书里谈到过人们
with personal branding is it that it's
对个人品牌的最大误解，那就是认为个人品牌就是
this kind of pursuit for fame whereas
追求名利。而真正优秀的
great personal branding isn't
个人品牌并非
self-promotion it's idea promotion it's
自我推销，而是理念推广。
this is what I believe this is my
这就是我的
perspective gather around if you think
观点。如果你也这么认为，那就围过来。如果你觉得
the same self-promotion sounds like we
自我推销听起来像是“我们
just won an award last night at the
昨晚在
marketing Awards and you're all on the
营销奖上得了奖，你们都站在
table taking the selfie we are amazing
桌子上自拍，我们太棒了”，那根本
that doesn't cultivate a personal brand
算不上个人品牌。
personal brand is this is my perspective
个人品牌是我
on the world um if you've got the same
对世界的看法。嗯，如果你也有同样的
perspective which we call idea promotion
看法，也就是我们所说的理念推广，
come join me it's not look at me it's
那就加入我吧。这不是“看我”，而是“
look at this yes it's not chasing the
看这个”。是的，这不是追逐
spotlight it's becoming a spotlight and
聚光灯，而是成为聚光灯，
spotlighting the thing that matters most
照亮最重要的事物，
and it's it's shining the light on
照亮
something else especially on an idea so
其他事物，尤其是理念。
we see people online who are Shameless
我们经常在网上看到一些厚颜无耻的
self-promoters I went to the gym today
自我推销者：“我今天去健身房了，
look at my avocado on toast with chili
看看我的牛油果吐司配辣椒
flakes and they're saying look at me
片！” 他们总是说“看我，
look at me look at me and the people
看我，看我”，而
that we most want to follow are the ones
我们最想追随的人，却是那些
who say don't look at me look at this
说“别看我，看看这个，看看这个
this is what's going on in the world and
世界正在发生什么，看看这个，
this is what you should you should be
你应该为此感到
excited about this um and and that's the
兴奋”的人。这就是
difference because on the surface we
区别所在。因为表面上看，我们
might see you and say oh you know
可能会说：“哦，你知道，
Steven's all about like look at Steven
史蒂文的一切都是为了‘看史蒂文’”，但事实并非如此。
point if if you think it's about that
如果你认为事情就是这样，那就大错特错了。
you've missed the point he's shining a
他是在关注
the world and he's bringing stuff into
世界上正在发生的事情，他把这些事情带到
the spotlight he's not trying to say
聚光灯下。他不是在说“
check me out he's saying check this out
看我”，而是在说“看看这个”。
it's interesting that the podcast was
有趣的是，播客是
the most accelerating thing for my
我
personal brand and it's really bringing
个人品牌发展最快的加速器，它真的把
people here and then do my very best to
人们聚集到这里。我会尽我
listen as much as I can which is
所能多听一些内容，这很
interesting right because we've kind of
有意思，对吧？因为我们
cultivated it's almost like the campfire
营造了一种氛围，就像围坐在篝火旁一样，越来越
we've cultivated more people sat around
多的人围坐在
the campfire listening to conversations
篝火旁聆听这样的对话。在
like this it is incredible that these
这个
times that we're in these are the
时代，这真是不可思议。 我们现在进行的这些
conversations that would have been
对话，在
behind closed doors 20 years ago and you
20年前只能在闭门会议中进行，如果你
be able to sit and listen in on those
能旁听这些
chats and now they've been democratized
谈话，那将是一种莫大的荣幸。而现在，这种
these type of high level conversation
高水平的对话，这种
you share with the world uh you've
你与世界分享的对话，已经民主化了。你让
democratized something that was once a
曾经只有
very elite activity and you've made it
精英才能参与的活动变得大众化，让
people I've I've come to learn
每个人都能自由获取。
especially over the last couple of years
尤其是在过去几年里，我逐渐意识到
about the importance of people you
人的重要性。你在
beginning of this conversation hiring
对话一开始就谈到了人，招聘
people finding the right people to join
人才，找到合适的人加入
you in your mission how Central to being
你的团队，共同实现你的使命。组建合适的团队对于
successful in both business but just
商业乃至
more broadly in life is assembling the
更广泛的人生都至关重要。
right group of people so business is a
商业是一项
team sport there's no there's no getting
团队运动，这一点毋庸置疑。
around it I don't believe in
我不相信
solopreneurship I don't believe that you
单打独斗，我不认为你
can be a oneperson entrepreneur I think
可以成为一个单枪匹马的企业家。我认为
entrepreneurs are team players and that
企业家都是团队成员，他们会
they assemble teams um they put together
组建团队，他们会组建由
teams of amazing people sometimes they
优秀人才组成的团队。有时，他们一
the beginning and then they become
开始会组建由普通人组成的团队，然后这些人也会成长为
amazing people so I'm a believer that
优秀的人才。 我相信，
two person co-founders or a Founder plus
两人联合创始人或一位创始人加
an assistant is a great place to start
一位助理是组建团队的绝佳起点，之后可以组建
four person campaign teams eight person
四人团队、八人
core teams 30 person performance teams
核心团队或三十人绩效团队。
so I love the British military's
我非常欣赏英国军队的
approach to team building uh so in the
团队建设方式。
British military they have two person
英国军队的团队编制是：两人
scout team four person fire Team 8
侦察队、四人火力队、八
person section 30 person platoon so they
人班、三十人排，所以是
go 2 4
2、4、8、30。
830 and um I I've used that myself in my
我自己也在
own scaleup approach where if if there's
创业初期运用了这种模式。如果有个
a new idea we put two people on it once
新想法，我们会先安排两个人负责；一旦想法被
it's proven four people are on it once
验证可行，就增加到四个人；一旦项目步入
it's up and running eight people are on
正轨，就增加到八人；
it once it becomes a business that has
一旦项目发展成为拥有
its own Standalone value 30 people are
独立价值的企业，就增加到三十人，
on it so it's
所以是
24830 um and that's been um that's been
2、4、8、30。这其实是借鉴了
a British military learning uh that that
英国军队的经验。
I that I kind of went well if they've
如果他们已经
done 400 years of HR experiments why
进行了400年的人力资源实验，
wouldn't I just learn from how they
我为什么不直接学习他们是如何
organize their teams is there anything
组织团队的呢？
you've found that is consistent across
你有没有发现，在
all of the best people you've hired
你招聘、共事、
co-founded a company with partnered with
共同创立公司或合作过的所有优秀人才身上，有什么共同点？
is there any consistent thing I'm I'm
我
always looking for complimentary
一直在寻找互补的
energies so here's what I'm looking
能量。所以，我一直在寻找的是这样的：
for uh in the deck of cards there's four
扑克牌有四种
suits so you got clouds so head in the
花色，分别是云朵（代表头脑清晰）、黑桃（代表执行力）、
connecting with people diamonds money
红心（代表人际交往）、方块（代表金钱和
Finance data so I always look for a
财务数据）。所以，我一直在寻找一个
balanced team of someone who's Visionary
平衡的团队，团队成员包括：一位富有远见的人，一位像
with someone who's a Spades person doing
黑桃一样负责执行的人；一位善于沟通的人，一位负责
connector with someone who money or or
金钱或
data so I'm looking to try and perfectly
数据的人。我希望
balance my team with the four suits and
我的团队能够完美地平衡这四种花色。
I've seen Visionary people who get
我见过一些富有远见的人，
nothing done because they don't have an
因为缺乏
implementor around I've seen amazing
执行者而一事无成；我也见过一些优秀的
connectors who don't have anyone
沟通者，因为缺乏平衡者而错失良机，最终
balancing them out so they never retain
无法留住
any of the money that's flowing around
周围的资源。 他们
networker people are doing deals around
围绕着这些交易做事，
them but they're not involved in any of
但他们自己却不参与其中。
it so for me it's the it's the
对我来说，关键在于
connection between those four energies
这四种能量之间的联系。
and when you get all four en
当这四种能量
firing um and in one team then you get
在一个团队中都得到充分发挥时，你就能
the value creation and retention let's
创造价值并留住人才。我们来
talk about money let's talk about it
谈谈钱吧。
UK and many countries around the world
英国正处于生活成本危机之中，世界上许多国家都处于衰退之中
are either in or on the brink of
或濒临
recession so one of the most popular
衰退。因此，在
in the last 3 to six months is about
过去三到六个月里，我们CEO面试中被问到最多的问题之一就是关于
money people's concern about their own
钱的问题。人们担心自己的
money spending finance and saving if I'm
钱，包括支出、财务和储蓄。如果我是一个
worth of disposable income every month
每月只有100美元或1000美元可支配收入的人，
or if I have a, or
或者如果我有
0,000 what should I be thinking about as
10000美元，那么我应该考虑什么才能
it relates to creating more money and
创造更多财富，
making myself financially free the first
实现财务自由呢？首先，
thing is you just want to earn more um
你只想赚更多钱。
people massively settle for how much
人们往往满足于
they could earn um so the first place to
自己能赚多少钱。所以
I think to invest is in yourself but
我认为，首先应该投资的是自己。但
here's the first principle the first
这里有一个基本原则：
principle is uh income follows assets
收入会随之而来。 资产
income follows assets means that the
带来收入，这意味着
more assets you have the more income
你拥有的资产越多，
you'll earn if I own if I want rental
你赚到的收入就越多。如果我拥有资产，想要获得租金
income first I need a house if I want
收入，首先我需要一套房子；如果想要获得
dividend income I need shares um if I
股息收入，我需要股票；如果
want to be paid as a brand ambassador
想要作为品牌大使获得报酬，
first I need a brand so essentially the
首先我需要一个品牌。所以本质上，
more we can accumulate assets the more
我们积累的资产越多，
easy and effortless the money flows so
资金流动就越轻松顺畅。因此，
um we have to figure out well what
我们必须弄清楚
assets could you accumulate and what
你可以积累哪些资产，以及
assets could you formalize and own I
你可以将哪些资产正式化并拥有。我
wrote a book called 24 assets and I
写了一本书，叫做《24种资产》，我
listed out all the different digital
列出了所有不同的数字
assets that are new economy assets that
资产，也就是
people could have things like brand and
人们可以拥有的新经济资产，比如品牌和定位、
positioning things like databases things
数据库，以及
like company culture is an asset now so
现在也被视为资产的企业文化。
I talk about how do you formalize those
我会讨论如何将这些资产正式化。
things if someone's just starting out
如果有人刚起步，
and they've got 100 a month to be to be
每月只有100美元，说实话，如果
perfectly honest trying to invest 100 a
试图每月投资100美元，那
month or any of that it's not going to
不会有任何效果，也
do anything it's not going to change
不会改变
your life but if you put that into your
你的生活。但如果你把这笔钱投入到提升
own skills and your own development um
自身技能和发展中，
let's say you don't have negotiation
比如说你缺乏谈判
skills well there are courses that you
技巧，那么你
can take for $100 that give you
可以参加相关的课程。 花100美元就能提升你的
negotiation skills let's say you don't
谈判技巧。比如说，如果你不
know how to close sales you can take a a
知道如何促成交易，你可以参加
course on how to make sales let's say
销售课程；如果
you don't feel confident public speaking
你不擅长公开演讲，
you could do a public speaking course um
你可以参加演讲课程。
so there are things that allow you to
所以，有很多方法可以
gain your skills the other thing too is
提升你的技能。另外，
money is relationships so if you don't
金钱也与人脉息息相关。如果你
have a lot of money you typically don't
没有很多钱，通常你的
have a lot of relationships um you might
人脉也不多。你可能
have a limited number of relationships
只有有限的人脉，
or a limited number of relationships
或者只有少数几个能带来
with people who have a flow of money
资金的人。但
when you have a high degree of
如果你和那些
money flowing it's very effortless for
资金充裕的人保持着良好的关系，那么资金的流入和流出都会非常容易。
that to flow to and from you as well so
所以，
you might have to invest in
你可能需要投资于
relationships um when I arrived in the
人脉关系。我刚到
UK I knew that uh one of the places that
英国的时候就知道，
I would meet interesting people would be
结识有趣的人的地方之一就是
private Banks so I didn't qualify for
私人银行。虽然我不符合
private bank but I went into a private
私人银行的资格，但我还是去了一家私人
bank and I said I'm going to be
银行，我说我即将
launching a business and of course it's
创业，而且肯定会
going to be great and successful I want
非常成功，我想在
to bank with a private bank um can I do
私人银行开户。请问
you have an entrepreneurs program oh
你们有针对企业家的账户吗？ 哦，对，我们参加了那个项目，
yeah we did and they start selling me
他们开始向我
joining the entrepreneurs program now it
推销他们的创业者项目。
cost me £600 to open an account with
我花了600英镑在
that private bank but they immediately
那家私人银行开户，但他们立刻就
invited me to dinners and they invited
邀请我参加晚宴，还邀请
me to
我参加
people for a dinner party uh we're going
一个社交晚宴。呃，我们要在
to have had burgers on the boat and he
船上吃汉堡。
and he said oh great can I come and I
他说，哦，太好了，我可以来吗？我
said of course you can come it's your
说，当然可以，这是你的
boat right and so he said great that'll
船，对吧？他说，太好了，那肯定很棒。
be exciting so he basically said you can
所以他基本上是说，你可以，
you can host this party on on my 100
你可以在我的100英尺游艇上举办这个派对。
foot boat so I reached out to all the
于是我联系了所有我
people who I didn't know and I said hey
不认识的人，我说，嘿，
we're putting together burgers on the
我们要在船上准备汉堡，
boat would you like to come along and
你想来和
have some burgers with interesting
有趣的
people and then they came along and I
人一起吃汉堡吗？然后他们就来了，我算是对
made the investment into relationship um
人际关系进行投资了。嗯，
now the funny thing is a lot of people
有趣的是，很多人
will say oh but you know someone with
会说，哦，但是你知道，有人有
100 foot yacht funny thing is I I think
100英尺的游艇。有趣的是，我认为
plenty of people who have a boat
很多拥有游艇的人，
especially in Dubai it sits empty most
尤其是在迪拜，他们的船大部分时间都是空着的。
of the time you could reach out to 30
你可以联系30
people and say we're going to do it on
个人，告诉他们我们要…… 想象一下，在
someone's boat would you like it to be
别人的船上，你希望这艘船是
your boat with or without your energy so
你的吗？无论你是否愿意投入精力？所以，
making investments into
投资
relationships is a really powerful thing
人际关系真的非常重要。如果
for $100 a month personally what would I
每月有100美元，我个人会怎么
do with $100 a month take people out to
做？请人
dinner that would be my number one
吃饭，这将是我最重要的
investment i' I'd probably be taking
投资。我可能会请
people out to dinner why the investment
人吃饭，投资
into the relationship so I would be
人际关系。我会
inviting the most interesting people I
邀请我能邀请到的最有趣的人。
could possibly invite uh if I had the
嗯，如果我
ability for $100 a month I guess that's
每月有100美元，我想这足够请人吃
one dinner so I would reach out to
一顿饭了。我会联系一些
someone interesting and say I've seen
有趣的人，说：“我看过
your story I've seen what you're
你的故事，也了解你的
interested can I take you out for lunch
兴趣，我可以请你吃午饭吗？或者
can I take you out for dinner it's my
晚餐？我请客，
shout I'd love to get to know you a
我很想更了解你一些。”
little bit better obviously don't do
当然，不要邀请
that with someone who's famous you get a
名人，你
hundred of those a day I get plenty of
每天都会收到上百个名人的邀请，我
those a day reach out to someone who's
每天都会收到很多。联系那些
not famous but who's accomplished who's
不出名但有成就、
successful who's who's a mentores type
成功、可以指导你的
person not necessarily a superstar but
人，不一定是超级巨星，但
someone who's a few ahead take those
要比别人领先一些。邀请这些
people out to lunch take them out to
人。 午餐、
dinner would you say in that message
晚餐，你会在信息里说吗？
that you know you talk about calls I
你知道，你谈到电话，我
talk about emails what what would
谈到邮件，
someone have to say to you considering
考虑到
where you are in your life now with all
你现在的生活状态，以及
the inquiries you get for you to
你收到的所有邀请，如果有人真的想和你一起喝
actually go for a coffee with
咖啡，你会怎么说？
um so bear in mind everyone's going to
嗯，记住，每个人都会给
email you and say this yeah well it
你发邮件说这些。是的，
happened today actually someone said um
今天就发生了这样的事。有人说：“
Daniel I noticed in the background of
丹尼尔，我注意到
one of your photos that you have an
你的一张照片背景里有一把
amazing Fender Strater I teach people
很棒的Fender Stratocaster吉他。我教别人
how to play guitar um I would love the
弹吉他，我很想有
opportunity to do a guitar lesson with
机会教你一节吉他课，
you and help you to shred on that guitar
帮
you how to play some guitar and I
你练练吉他。”这真的很好。他以前看过我的播客，注意到了我的吉他，他主动联系我，这对我来说很有意义。他说：“我很想和你聊聊，教你弹吉他。”
obviously I'll have a chat with him
当然，我会一边和他聊天一边教他。
while we do that but that was a really
这感觉真的很好，感觉我们之间建立了
very it felt like a a good connection I
很好的联系。我
also had a look at his um profile and he
还看了他的个人资料，他
looked like a really lovely person you
看起来是个很可爱的人。
know who's who's getting on with doing
谁在忙着做事，还有
stuff there's a bit of With Or Without
点“有你或没
You energy as well in terms of you know
你”的感觉，你知道，
I can see this person's up to stuff so I
我能看出这个人正在做些事情，所以我
look at that and I go he did some
观察一下，然后想，他肯定
research on you mhm he offered you value
对你做了些调查，嗯，他在
in an area where you were potentially
你可能正在
seeking or looking for the value yep oh
寻找价值的领域为你提供了价值，是的，哦，
that's definitely true if you've seen me
如果你看过我弹吉他，那肯定没错，
guitar but that's that's like the corol
但这就像是社交
component and I I feel the same way that
元素，我也有同样的感觉，我
I I I try and figure out why sometimes I
试着弄明白为什么有时候我会
reply to these cold Outreach messages
回复这些陌生的外联信息，
but 99.9% of the time I don't and it
但99.9%的情况下我不会。通常情况下，
tends to be the case that the person
对方
will say they'll show that they've done
会说他们会证明他们
some kind of research on me which is
对我做了一些调查，这很能满足
good for your ego like everyone has an
你的自尊心，毕竟每个人都有
ego you want to feel like someone
自尊心，你会想要感觉有人
actually cares and then they'll offer me
真的关心你，然后他们会给我
something in return for by way do you
一些回报。对了，你
know I did this to you I don't know even
知道吗，我以前也对你做过这件事，我不知道
know if you remember you and I were both
你是否还记得，你和我都是
speakers at a conference right and we
一个会议的演讲者，对吧？我们
were in the elevator and i' prepared for
在电梯里，我为
you a really nice leather um briefcase
你准备了…… 那是一个非常漂亮的皮质公文包，里面装着
and it had your I created the happy sexy
你之前提到的“快乐性感
millionaire thing and we we gave all the
百万富翁”的宣传品。我们给所有
speakers one of those you weren't that
演讲者都准备了一个，你其实没那么
special we had we had something for all
特别，我们给每个人都准备了一份。
the but anyway it was interesting cuz I
不过，这事儿挺有意思的，因为我之前也跟你做过类似的事情，但我们后来都没再联系
never ended up following up with you and
你，
you never followed up with us but here's
你也没联系我们。但
here's the thing I want to share that no
我想分享的是，
I want to share that because sometimes
有时候事情就是
it doesn't work right sometimes you have
不顺利，有时候你必须主动
to send out like when I sent out 3,000
出击。比如，我之前给洛杉矶创业公司发了3000条
cold DMS to LA launch a business I
陌生邮件，我
didn't expect 3,000 people to respond I
没指望3000人回复，我
expected 30 or 40 people to come back to
估计会有30到40人回复。
me when I gave gave that to you do you
我把公文包送给你的时候，你还
remember it I remember getting a
记得吗？我记得我收到一个
briefcase and I'm trying to I do I do
公文包，我
quite a lot of public speaking these
最近经常做公开演讲，
days so um we only had like a five like
所以我们只有大概两
a two-minute interaction and I said hey
分钟的交流。我说：“嘿，
this is a little gift for you inside
这是给你准备的小礼物，里面
we've created something for you have a
我们为你准备了一些东西，
look um was it something I had to scan
看看吧。” 里面有什么需要扫描的东西吗？是的。
yeah we' we'd built you a little landing
我们当时给你做了一个小型落地
page campaign yes I remember yeah I
页推广活动，是的，我记得。我
remember getting in the car and saying
记得我上了车，
to my team oh this is cool yeah and then
跟我的团队说，哦，这很酷。然后
of course it gets past of the team and
当然，团队也同意了，
they're like yeah yeah fair enough put
他们说，是是是，好吧，把它也算在“
that on the pile of cool things um so
酷事”清单里吧。所以
the point is is I'm saying that to say
重点是，我想说的是，在做
these things you don't want to get hung
这些事情的时候，你不要
up on the idea that one person's like in
纠结于这样一个想法：在
that same event we gave that same thing
同样的活动中，我们把同样的东西给了
to another really well-known person
另一个非常知名的人，他们接受了，然后说，
you know millions of followers and
你知道，他们有几百万粉丝，
they're one of our clients now so we
现在也是我们的客户了。所以我们
have wither without you energy which is
有“没有你，一切都会好起来”的能量。
when when my team do this we pick 30 or
我的团队做这件事的时候，我们会挑选30到
40 people who'd make a amazing
40个能为
connections and contacts in our VIP
我们VIP
Outreach team and then we reach out to
拓展团队建立重要联系的人，然后我们联系
them and we expect maybe two or three of
他们，我们预计其中可能有两三个人会
them to get back to us so it's that idea
回复我们。所以，我的意思是，
of you know don't like if someone
如果有人
messages you and you don't message back
给你发消息，你没有回复，
it's not the end of the world there are
这不是世界末日，
other people you can message and there's
你还可以联系其他人，而且……
a and look what happens there you go it
事情就是这样，循环往复，
comes around again it always comes
总是会
around again if it's if it's meant to
循环往复。如果命中注定，它就会
happen it'll happen so what about people
发生。那么，
you know so many members of my team
你认识的人呢？我的很多团队成员都来
speak to me and ask me about investing
问我投资方面的问题，
they have tens of thousands to invest or
他们有几万美元可以投资什么的。
whatever but I'm curious about your
但我很好奇你的
personal investment thesis with a with a
个人投资理念。如果你
capital that you have spare what do you
有闲置资金，你会怎么利用
do with it to create more money
它来创造更多财富？
so what does your portfolio look like
你的投资组合是什么样的？
it's extremely boring I stick any
非常无聊，我把所有
available Capital into S&amp;P 500 what's
可用的资金都投入了标普500指数。
the S&amp;P 500 for anyone that doesn't yeah
标普500是什么？对于不了解的人来说，它就是
the top 500 stocks in the US so
美国排名前500的股票。
essentially any government that inflates
基本上，
its currency anywhere in the world that
世界上任何地方的政府如果让本国货币贬值，这些
money will hit the economy and it will
钱就会流入经济，
eventually make its way back to the top
最终会通过消费或其他方式回到美国排名前
500 companies in the US through spending
500的公司，或者这些
or that Capital will end up being put
资金最终会
into the S&amp;P 500 which inflates so one
流入标普500指数，而标普500指数本身也会贬值。所以无论如何，这些钱最终都会
way or another it's going back to the
回到
top 500 companies in the US so it's
美国排名前500的公司。因此，
almost impossible to beat the S&amp;P 500 I
几乎不可能跑赢标普500指数。我
hate investing it's not my thing I like
讨厌投资。 这不是我的风格，我喜欢
expansive business creation I'm an
大兴土木，我是个
optimist uh great investors are often
乐观主义者。呃，优秀的投资者往往是
pessimist they're very good at thinking
悲观主义者，他们非常擅长思考
what could go wrong and they analyzing
可能出错的地方，并分析
risk I hate that [__] so for me
风险。我讨厌那种东西。所以就我
personally I want to as much as possible
个人而言，我希望尽可能地
expand the portfolio of businesses that
拓展
I think should exist in the world and
我认为应该存在于世上的商业组合。
I've always made my money by just saying
我一直以来赚钱的方式就是，仅仅因为
I romantically like the idea of this
我浪漫地喜欢某个商业想法，就
my energy into it and it's going to
全身心投入其中，让它
become worth millions rather than think
价值数百万美元。而不是
about where I want to invest money I
去想我想把钱投到哪里，我
want to create something that's
想创造一些
investable for other people to put money
其他人愿意投资的东西，
into because that's how you really make
因为这才是真正
money so the exciting thing is not
赚钱的方式。所以，令人兴奋的不是
placing my own chips the exciting thing
把自己的筹码投
to place chips in into that so let's
进去，而是创造一些其他人愿意投资的东西。那么，我们来
talk about that Journey then yep that
谈谈这段旅程吧。没错，这段
Journey from got an idea want to start
旅程始于一个想法：我想开
that ice cream business that Chilean
一家冰淇淋店，一家智
basil ice cream business whatever except
利罗勒冰淇淋店，等等，除了
for tens of millions except for tens of
几千万美元，除了几
millions it I I get off the ground
千万美元，如果我的店开张了，
people love my chile and basil ice cream
人们喜欢我的智利罗勒冰淇淋，那么，这段
what what is the journey that anrea goes
旅程是什么？ 这个领域
on from zero up until they exit so
从零开始，直到他们退出。所以，
there's there's a key stages the first
这里有一个关键阶段，前
four stages where everyone gets caught
四个阶段，每个人都会陷入
is called chaos concept audience offer
混乱，这被称为“概念、受众、产品/服务、
sales so you have to develop your
销售”。因此，你必须发展你的
concept so it's a good concept youel Val
概念。一个好的概念需要你
ated it you've conducted some
评估它、进行一些
experiments you're aligned to it other
实验、与它保持一致，并且其他
people are excited about it audience is
人也对它感到兴奋。受众是指你吸引
that you engage an audience waiting
受众的方式，例如建立等候
lists dinner parties uh scorecards
名单、举办晚宴、评分卡、
quizzes discussion groups all of those
测验、讨论小组等等，所有这些都是
are great audience Builders y um offer
很好的受众构建方式。产品/服务
is that you construct a packaged up
是指你构建一个打包的
offering so that people can buy
产品/服务，以便人们可以购买，
something and that they that audience
并且受众
can now act on something and buy and
现在可以采取行动并购买。
then sales which is the ability to talk
销售是指
and discuss with your interested parties
与感兴趣的人交谈和讨论以
to Clos deals to actually get sales
达成交易的能力，从而真正完成销售，
across the line and to do that
并且要
predictably and reliably so for sales we
可预测且可靠地完成销售。因此，在销售方面，我们
established something called a rhythm of
建立了一个叫做“销售节奏”的东西，包括
laps leads appointments presentations
线索、预约、演示
and sales and we measure our pipeline
和销售。我们每周都会衡量我们的销售渠道，例如线索
every week how many leads how many
数量、
appointments how many presentations how
预约数量、演示数量和
many sales so those are the first four
销售数量。以上就是前四个
things concept audience offer sales and
方面：概念、受众、产品/服务、销售。
of Revenue just by doing that the next
仅仅做到这些，就应该能让你获得六位数的收入。接下来
thing is about team building you've got
是关于团队建设。 你需要
to establish a key person of influence
确立一位关键人物，他/她
who's got a personal brand Who's lead
拥有个人品牌，能够
the leader of the company who's going to
领导公司，
embody the brand and you got to build a
并成为品牌的化身。你需要围绕他/她组建一个
team of eight people around them um a
八人团队，包括
general manager Marketing in sales
总经理、市场营销、销售、
Finance admin um uh it media and
财务、行政、IT、媒体和
operations those kind of roles and
运营等职位。
essentially you now build this core team
基本上，你现在要建立这个八人核心团队，而
of eight and um the key person of
关键人物的
influence job is to engage bigger and
职责是吸引越来越
bigger audiences and so they get out
多的受众。因此，他/她要走
there and tell the story of the business
出去，讲述公司的故事，
they get on stages they pitch um they
登上舞台，进行项目推介，
publish content they raise their profile
发布内容，提升知名度，
they do joint ventures and Partnerships
开展合资和合作项目。他/她
so they're leading from the front while
身先士卒，而
the general manager or Ops director is
总经理或运营总监则
making sure things don't fall apart
负责确保团队运作顺畅。
behind once you hit about eight people
一旦团队达到八人左右，
you now have to digitize absolutely
你就必须将
everything of value in that business so
公司所有有价值的东西数字化。
now you go through the whole process of
接下来，你需要完成整个
digitization of the value so you're
价值数字化流程，为
getting ready to scale which means for
规模化发展做好准备。这意味着，
example moving physical relationships to
例如，将实体关系转移到客户关系管理系统（
a CRM some kind of data database or
CRM）或某种数据库，或者
building a CRM uh formalizing your
构建CRM系统，规范你的
intellectual property um building a
知识产权，打造
brand a company brand um formalizing
公司品牌，规范
your organizational culture uh getting
你的组织文化。 嗯，建立
into um really good investor
良好的投资者
relationship and and documentation
关系和完善文件
governance so all of these are
管理，所有这些都是为了
developing systems developing assets of
发展业务系统和资产，例如
the business um having online marketing
拥有在线营销
and sales systems having an online way
和销售系统，能够可靠地在线
of generating a lot of leads reliably
生成大量潜在客户，以及能够
having an online way of making customers
让客户在大多数情况下都感到
mostly happy most of the time so you're
满意。所以，你
basically trying to build as many assets
基本上是在努力构建尽可能多的资产。当
as possible what you're trying to do at
你团队规模在
about 8 to 10 people is raise revenue
8到10人左右时，你的目标是提高
per person so let's say you got 10
人均收入。假设你有10
people with 100,000 per person so you
个人，每人年收入10万美元，那么总
got a million of Revenue 10 people times
收入就是100万美元。10个人乘以10万美元，就是
100,000 million of Revenue if you can
100万美元的收入。如果你能
add assets and get it to go to 1.1 1.2
增加资产，让收入达到110万美元、120万美元甚至13万美元，
1.3 million now you've got 130,000 per
那么人均收入就达到了13万美元。
person so what you're trying to do is
所以，你要做的就是
add as many digital assets as possible
尽可能多地增加数字资产，以
revenue per person up once you see that
提高员工人均收入。一旦你看到
the revenue per person is going up now
人均收入在增长，
you can add people because the more
你就可以增加员工了，因为数字资产越多，人均收入就越高。
successful now the really hard jump is
现在，真正的挑战来了。
from 12 to 30 from 12 people to 30
从12人到30人的飞跃，规模
you're too big to be small too small to
太大，无法再小；规模太小，无法再
be big very difficult time in any
大。这是任何企业都会面临的艰难时期。
business's life um and what you have to
你需要
do is go through a transformation of a
做的，是将一支由
small team of rebels and misfits to a
叛逆者和不合群的人组成的小团队，转型为一支能够
manufacturing value a lot of people have
创造价值的专业团队。不幸的是，很多人
to go unfortunately some of the earlier
不得不离开。一些早期
people who were there because they could
员工，因为他们还
breathe and had a pulse and all of that
活着，
stuff they uh unfortunately have to go
他们不得不另谋出路。
find a new startup and you now have to
现在，你必须通过
through recruiters with a proper process
正规的招聘流程，从猎头那里招募团队成员，让他们经历完整的入
they're on boarded correctly and now you
职流程，确保他们顺利融入团队。一旦达到30人，你就
transform into a more valuable
转型为一个更有价值的
Professional Organization once you hit
专业组织。
30 you've got a five person executive
你将拥有一个五人执行
team plus a non-executive director and
团队，外加一名非执行董事和
an advisor and then you've got some
一名顾问，以及若干个
teams of teams and now you're doing 10
团队的团队。现在，你的
million of Revenue 3 million of profit
营收达到1000万美元，利润达到300万美元，
and now you're exible have you got to
你拥有更大的灵活性。你是否应该更早地
make a decision earli that was a
做出决定？ 真是
mouthful it's so true it's so it's so
一言难尽，太对了，太
funny did you agree with that all of it
搞笑了。你完全同意吗？
I agreed with all of it the interesting
我完全同意。还有一点很有意思，
thing as well is the part you said about
你提到
of the first 10 people you hire very few
你最初招的10个人里，很少有人
of them are equipped or ready or able to
能
adjust to the environment you have at 30
适应
40 50 60 100t and it's and part of the
30、40、50、60甚至100人规模的环境。
re what I've noticed is that when
我注意到，当团队
there's 10 people you're requiring a
只有10个人的时候，你需要的是
different set of skills and you're
一套不同的技能，你会
you're thinking more about multi
更多地考虑那些身兼多职、多
multidisiplinary individuals that can
学科的人才，他们能
kind of wear a few hats but not do
胜任好几件事，但又没有哪一项特别出色。就像
anything exceptionally well Swiss Army
瑞士军刀一样，
knives they can do 25 things badly yeah
他们能做好25件事，但都做得不好。没错，就是这样。而
exactly and then when you get to like 50
当团队规模达到50、60甚至
60 70 people it's really specialist
70人时，就需要真正的专家了。
Specialists bread knife bread knife Cuts
专家就像面包刀，能把
bread really well just that so on this
面包切得特别好，仅此而已。所以，
then when we're thinking about our own
当我们思考自己的
careers we've got to ask ourselves that
职业生涯时，我们必须问问自己：
question which is are we a specialist
我们是否是适合
that should be going into a company
进入一家需要专家的公司？
where there's 50 60 70 people or are we
50、60、70 个人？还是我们
should be playing in startups and then
应该像瑞士军刀一样，在创业公司里扮演
going from zero to one versus like one
从零到一的角色，而不是从一到
to two yeah I have I've had to wrestle
两的角色？是的，我曾经也纠结过这个问题。
that with that myself I personally
我个人
absolutely adore the first 2 million of
非常喜欢最初的 200 万美元
Revenue that's that is where my fun that
营收，那才是真正让
for me is fun it's where I find it
我兴奋、充满乐趣的时刻。
distracted once we hit 2 million of
一旦营收达到 200 万美元，我几乎会病态地分心，
Revenue and I have to remind myself oh
不得不提醒自己：
wait a second we've got a fast growth
等等，我们正处于快速增长期，
business here stop thinking about other
别再想其他
things I really enjoy getting businesses
事情了。我真的很享受帮助企业
past that first couple hundred thousand
突破每月几十万美元的营收瓶颈，
a month and then for whatever reason I'm
然后不知为何，我就像在
like dreaming of a blank page I just
做白日梦一样，脑子里总是
want some like what if we did this what
想着“如果我们这样做会怎样？
if we did that but here's the cool thing
如果我们那样做会怎样？”。但有趣的是，
there are so many amazing people who are
有很多优秀的人
phenomenal at the 2 to 20 million jump
在 200 万到 2000 万美元的营收增长阶段表现卓越。
so at the moment the person who's
目前，
leading Dent Global is Glenn Carlson
领导 Dent Global 的是 Glenn Carlson，
Glenn is I've known him since I was 14
我从 14 岁就认识他了。
years old and actually what he's
事实上，他目前最
phenomenal at at the moment we've
擅长的是…… 我
discovered is that he's really really
发现他真的很
good at driving that next jump the 2 to
擅长实现下一个飞跃，从200万美元到
20 million jump so there's the Z to
2000万美元的飞跃。所以，有Z2，有
there's the 0 to 200 Grand like testing
0到20万美元的测试，
there's the 200 Grand to 2 million which
有20万美元到200万美元的测试，这就像是，
is like yeah okay this thing's got some
好吧，这东西有
legs there's the 2 million to 20 million
潜力，还有200万美元到2000万美元的
jump which is we're professionalizing
飞跃，这意味着我们正在走向专业化，
we're become a proper business um we're
我们正在成为一家真正的企业，我们正在
becoming valuable we're getting all the
变得有价值，我们正在招揽所有
right people what's shocked me because
合适的人才。让我震惊的是，因为
I've known Glenn for so many years is
我认识格伦这么多年了，
that we've just recently discovered that
我们刚刚重新…… 最近发现
that's what he's suited to he's really
他很适合做这个，他真的很
good at the 2 to 20 million jump he's so
擅长从200万用户跳到2000万用户，他非常
good at recruiting talented people he's
擅长招募人才，
so good at pushing them through a
非常擅长引导他们通过一个筛选
process that weeds out like 15 amazing
过程，这个过程会从15个优秀的
people down to two amazing people down
人才中筛选出2个，最终只剩下
to one how would you make the case to
一个。你会如何向
someone that's just heard what you've
一个刚听过你
said about your companies and that you
对公司描述以及你
like that 0 to2 million phas what case
喜欢从0到200万用户阶段的人解释呢？
would you make to me to admit what I'm
你会如何说服我为了
not good at for the sake of my business
我的事业承认我的不足之处？
because everyone can relate like I don't
因为每个人都能感同身受。我不想在
mean to share this without asking him
没问过他的情况下就分享这些，
but I'm sure like he's in control of the
但我相信他掌握着
edit so he can take it out if he doesn't
剪辑权，所以如果他不喜欢，他可以删掉。
like it did you think I was going to do
你觉得我会这么做吗？
it Jack turned around to our team the
杰克前几天转身对我们的团队说了这件事，
moment since he said it Jack said you
自从他说了那句话之后，我已经和很多人谈过这件事了。杰克说，你
know what um Jack's run this podcast
知道吗？杰克从零开始运营这个播客，
from zero so zero subscribers to where
从零订阅用户发展到
it is now 5 million subscribers Jack
现在的500万订阅用户。杰克在
turned around at 5 million subscribers
500万订阅用户的时候转身说……
and was like I'm not the best in the
我不是
world at doing lighting so what I've
世界上最好的灯光师，所以我去找了
someone who's the best at lighting and
一位灯光大师，让他
they're going to teach me they're going
教我，重新
to redesign my set 5 million subscribers
设计我的布景。他有500万订阅者，他
he's getting someone else to redesign a
找人重新设计
set so that the lighting is amazing it
布景，让灯光效果惊艳。要把胜利放在自负之上，
takes a certain kind of person to put
需要一种特殊的人格。
winning over ego I love that yeah you
我喜欢这一点，你
know what I mean and and I I think about
知道我的意思。而且，我想了
there's so many You Know Jack probably
很多。你知道，杰克可能
didn't know the profoundness of that
并不了解那
moment to me but someone who is
一刻对我而言的意义，但一个被
applauded from every oh you've built the
所有人称赞的人，比如“你打造了
best you know whatever for him to go you
最好的”，却能做到这样，你
know what there's so much I don't know
知道吗？有很多东西，我不知道。
he he role modeled humility and he role
他树立了谦逊的榜样，他
modeled um the idea of winning is better
树立了“胜利比正确更重要”的榜样。是的，
than uh being right right yeah um and
而且，
overing is not underlings that a great
领导不是下属。一个伟大的
company is great because you bring in
公司之所以伟大，是因为它招揽的是领导，而
overing not underlings uh so an
不是下属。下属是
as you are and an overing is someone
不如你的人，领导是
who's way better than you are so it's
比你强得多的人。 所以，正是
that confidence to bring in the overing
这种自信让我能够掌控一切。
um all of my businesses have been great
我的所有业务都做得很好，
because overing run them uh every
因为我掌控着它们。
everyone who is in my organization is
我团队里的每个人都比
way better than me at the thing they're
我更擅长他们
doing and I feel like like the conductor
所做的事情。我觉得就像
in the orchestra can't play all the
乐团的指挥不可能演奏所有
instruments and probably maybe is okay
乐器，可能只精通
at one instrument but actually their
一种乐器，但真正让他们成为
what makes them a great conductor the
伟大指挥的是他们能够招揽世界上最优秀的人才，也就是他们能够
ability to enroll people so the first
吸引人才的能力。所以，
thing I'd say is that there's value to
我想说的第一点是，
be made at every level if you're
每个层面都有创造价值的空间。如果你正在
watching
观看
this and you're you know you're not a
这段视频，而你又不是
founder and you're sitting there going
创始人，你可能会想，
all the people who make the money are
所有赚钱的人都是那些白手起家、把事业做起来的
the people who start from scratch and
人，
Daniel and look at Steven those guys are
看看丹尼尔和史蒂文，他们就是从
the zero to one guys wouldn't it be
零到一的创业者，
great if I was one of those but I'm not
如果我也是其中之一该多好啊！但我不是。
well actually that's not true the truth
其实，事实并非如此。
wealth to be created if you can take
如果你能把一个价值200万美元的项目发展到2000万美元，就能创造巨大的财富。如果你能做到这一点，
something from 2 to 20 million there's
就能获得
amazing wealth if you can take something
惊人的财富。 这可能涉及
from 20 to 200 million do you know this
2000万到2亿美元的投资。你知道吗？这
is worth mentioning one of the biggest
值得一提，这是
opportunities in the world right now
目前全球最大的机遇之一。
opportunities in the world but one of
全球有两大机遇，但目前
the biggest opportunities in the world
最大的机遇之一
at the moment is Baby Boomers who want
就是婴儿潮一代想要
to retire and a typical scenario is you
退休。一个典型的例子是，一位
get someone who's late 60s early 7s the
六十多岁或七十岁出头的人，他的
business had a high Watermark of a
企业曾经价值数
couple of million and now it's dropped
百万美元，但现在可能
down to maybe a million or six High six
跌到了一百万美元或六位数，
figures because the person's
因为他
semi-retiring and because the business
半退休了，而且企业一直在
has been on decline it's almost
走下坡路，几乎
unsalable the person wants to retire and
无法出售。他想退休，
they just want that business to go to
只想把企业交给
someone who's fresh um and what they're
一个有潜力的新人。他们
willing to do is to do a vendor sale
愿意做的就是进行卖方出售
exit Cody Sanchez who had she talks
退出。科迪·桑切斯（Cody Sanchez）谈到
about this I've done deals like this um
过这一点，他做过类似的交易。
and actually Jeremy with the 100 foot
实际上，杰里米（Jeremy）也用这种方法收购了一艘100英尺的
yacht that's how that's how he does it
游艇。
so you essentially you buy a business
本质上，你买下了一个
that the person wants to retire and you
想要退休的人的企业，然后
take over that business with fresh
接管它。 给这家企业注入新鲜
energy and you bring it back to its high
活力，让它重回
Watermark so there are so many people
巅峰。很多人
who what would be suited for is not
并不适合像
like me but they would actually go and
我一样从零开始，而是会
find you know Bill and Sarah who want to
去找像比尔和莎拉这样想要
retire and they want to do a deal where
退休的夫妇，他们希望达成一项协议，在
they get paid out over five years to
五年内分期付款，把
hand over the keys to the business let's
企业的钥匙交给别人。我们来仔细看看，
zoom in on this because a lot of people
因为很多人
don't understand the concept of like a
不理解
management buyout so I see Bill and
管理层收购的概念。比尔和
Sarah they're running a laundry mat yeah
莎拉经营着一家自助洗衣店。
life example from a friend of mine uh is
我有个朋友
called kit King and basically he uh
叫基特·金，他
approached someone who had that business
找到了一位经营自助洗衣店的老板，这家店的年营业额达到了几
million and then he the guy was ready to
百万美元。老板准备
retire when when he walked in the orders
退休时，他发现订单都是
would get printed out and put onto a
打印出来
spike and Spike number one was like this
贴在纸条上的，每个订单都对应一个“订单号”。订单
fulfilled it goes onto the fulfilled
完成后，会贴在“已完成
Spike uh piece of paper and then you
订单号”上。然后，
know he this young guy comes in and he
这位年轻人接手后，将
digitizes the business and he gets all
业务数字化，实现了所有
the automated order thing flowing cost
订单的自动化。 整个流程的优化花了
about 25 Grand to get in a specialist
大约2.5万英镑，请来了一位专家，他
who could do all of that and then he
能做所有这些工作。然后他
basically re-engage the team the team
重新激活了团队。团队当时
were totally un I think there's about a
完全一团糟，大概有
dozen people and they'd not had a team
十几个人，他们很久没开过团队
meeting in ages they' not they was no
会议了，
vision for the business they' not gone
对业务没有愿景，也
and spoken to customers in in forever
很久没和客户沟通了。
and then he comes in goes and talks to
然后他来了，
customers starts hosting some online
开始和客户交流，举办一些线上
events starts um sending out messages
活动，开始发送信息，
starts digitizing builds a bit of the
开始数字化转型，建立
brand and that business has I think
品牌。我认为，这家公司
grown like 500% in like 2 years it's
在两年内增长了500%，
massively successful but he started with
非常成功。但他是从一家已经运营了
years in that example you don't
年的公司起步的。在这个例子中，你
necessarily need any money no no no this
不一定需要任何资金，不，不，不，这完全不需要任何
was no money down so you can create a
启动资金。所以理论上，你可以从零开始创建一个价值数
multi-million pound business
百万英镑的企业。
remember that remember that money is
记住，金钱
just a database so it's a database of
只是一个数据库，一个
the value so what you do is like if I
价值的数据库。所以，就像我
want to buy a house I go to the bank and
想买房子，我就去银行，
they lend me the money to buy the house
他们贷款给我买房子；
if I want to buy a business the person
如果我想买一家企业，那么
who already owns the business is
已经拥有这家企业的人……
probably the most likely person to see
最有可能看到为这家
the value in funding the business a bank
企业提供资金价值的人可能是银行，银行
probably won't but the person who is
可能不会，但
selling it let's say I let's say I go to
出售企业的人，比如说，我去找
Bill and Sarah I say look there's no
比尔和莎拉，我说，毫无
question your business is worth 1.2
疑问，你们的企业价值120
million I don't have 1.2 million I have
万，但我没有120万，我只有
a little bit of money that I'm going to
一点钱，打算
invest into the business to grow it uh
投资到企业里发展壮大。
can I pay you the 1.2 million over 6
我可以分6年或7年支付你们120万吗？
this is my business plan you will be the
我的商业计划是这样的：你们将担任
board members chairperson of the board
董事会成员
and the business will uh be the security
和董事长，企业将作为
for that loan so if we screw grew up and
贷款的抵押品。这样，如果我们发展失败，
we can't make our payments you take the
无法按时还款，你们就可以
whole business back with everything that
收回整个企业，包括
we've thrown at it everything that we've
我们投入的所有资源和所做的一切。
back and sell it to somebody else if we
如果我们无法按时还款，你们可以把企业卖给其他人。
skip our payments um so you're securing
所以，你们是用
business itself you're doing a business
企业本身来担保购买，你们的商业
plan where it makes sense that the
计划确保企业
business could make the payments now
能够按时还款。现在，
think about it from Bill and Sarah's
从比尔和莎拉的
point of view they've got this thing
角度来看待这个问题。 他们觉得有件事让
that's driving them crazy they want to
他们抓狂：他们想
retire they want they want to go south
退休，想去
of France they want to go spend time
法国南部，想
with the grandkids and now someone's
和孙辈们待在一起。现在有人
coming along and saying yeah we're going
跑来说，我们会在
to pay you 120 Grand a year for the next
未来几年每年付给你12万美元，
s years and if we don't then you your
如果我们不履行承诺，就把你的
business back and if we don't you get
公司还给你。
the business back and if they believe
如果他们相信
you which is the key part if they
你——这才是关键——他们
believe in your ability to execute
相信你的执行能力。
because and if there's and if there's no
因为如果没有
one else offering anything else they
其他人提供其他方案，他们
believe you and there's no other options
相信你，也没有其他选择，那这笔交易就非常划算。
it's a great deal now there are here's
现在，有一个很
here's a crazy thing 65% of the value of
疯狂的事实：目前
all business equity in the economy is
经济中65%的商业股权价值都掌握在
owned by Baby Boomers right now so if
婴儿潮一代手中。所以，
you were to take if you were to throw a
如果你随机掷
dart board at all the valuation of every
飞镖，对
company in the UK or the USA there's a
英国或美国所有公司的估值进行预测，有
65% chance that you hit a baby boomer
65%的概率会击中婴儿潮一代的股东。这真是
right so it's it's it's incredible now
不可思议。现在，
all of those businesses have to be
所有这些企业都必须以某种方式
passed on somewhere now all of these
传承下去。 所有这些
young people they all want to have the
年轻人，他们都想拥有
latest psychedelic startup or you know
最新的迷幻创业公司，或者
something like that and they're like oh
类似的东西，他们会说，哦，
I don't want the elevator repair
我不想做那种
business that does 8 million a year you
年营业额800万的电梯维修生意，你
know it's like go get get involved in
知道，就像是去参与其中一样，对吧？
that right so that that's a huge
所以这是一个巨大的
opportunity mive the Arbitrage and
机会，可以进行套利，
opportunity here is boring businesses
机会就在这里，那些看似枯燥乏味的
boring businesses that you can you can
生意，你可以为它们
bring something to it you can digitize
带来一些东西，你可以让它数字化，
it you can make it interesting you can
你可以让它变得有趣，你可以
create a culture that's exciting the
创造一种令人兴奋的文化。关于
thing about a boring business boring
枯燥乏味的生意，比如婴儿潮
Boomer business boring Boomer business
一代的生意，对吧？
that get the URL I said that first
拿到网址了，我说的是第一个
trademark yeah could you guys grab the
商标，是的，你们能抢到
URL wait a second I'll
网址吗？等一下，我这就去拿。
get so the boring B business uh the bbbs
所以，枯燥乏味的生意，呃，
what you know a business can be exciting
你知道，一个生意也可以很精彩，
it can do a boring thing but still be an
它可以做一件枯燥的事情，但仍然可以是一个
exciting business you the way you run
精彩的生意。你管理
the team and the culture the the the the
团队的方式、你的企业文化，以及
money that it spits out can be exciting
它产生的收益都可以很精彩。
you can use that business to sponsor a
你可以用这个生意来赞助
charity you know I've got a a friend and
慈善机构。你知道，我有一个朋友兼
a client called Sebastian Bates he's got
客户叫塞巴斯蒂安·贝茨，他
an amazing martial arts school that's in
在英国有一家很棒的武术学校。 他在
the UK and Dubai called Warrior Academy
迪拜创办了勇士学院，
and he's used all of his he's very
并利用自己的所有资源，使之
profitable he's now set up martial arts
盈利颇丰。如今，他
schools in Kenya Nepal all of these
在肯尼亚、尼泊尔等多个
different areas that are um struggling
地区都开设了武术学校，这些地区原本都比较贫困，
areas now have a martial arts academy he
现在却都有了武术学院。
set up his own charity and he's
他还成立了自己的慈善机构，
basically doing martial arts uh schools
专门为那些
for kids who have never had any look out
从未接受过任何武术教育的孩子们提供武术学校。这些孩子
for them they're often Street kids and
通常是街头流浪儿或
homeless kids they come into martial
无家可归的孩子，他们来到这里学习
arts and they get taught life skills and
武术，不仅能掌握生活技能和
martial arts and confidence and
武术技巧，还能培养自信和
character but the point is is you can
品格。但重点是，你可以改变
take a boring business and the way that
一个看似枯燥的生意，通过
you run it you can do you can launch a
改变经营方式，你可以创办一个与之
charity uh associated with it you could
相关的慈善机构，你可以
hire young people who are coming out of
雇佣刚
prison and give them a second chance to
出狱的年轻人，给他们第二次机会重新
get started and that could be part of
开始，这本身就能成为
the excitement of the business there are
生意的亮点。有
so many ways to make a boring business
很多方法可以让一个枯燥的生意变得
an exciting business most of the times
精彩纷呈。大多数时候，
Bill and Sarah have given up on that
比尔和莎拉都放弃了这种想法，因为
they're just you know they've been doing
他们已经做了
it for 20 30 years they're not fresh
二三十年，经验不再丰富，
um and the business has been in Decline
而且生意也一直在走下坡路。
anyway that's a huge opportunity massive
这是一个巨大的机会，
way bigger than starting something new
远比创办一家新公司要好得多。
like if if I was starting from scratch
如果让我从零开始，
that's probably actually where I'd
这大概就是我真正的起点。想想真
start it's so funny that that never
可笑，当年
dawned on me when I was penniless in
我在
Manchester and I was very persuasive but
曼彻斯特身无分文的时候，竟然从未想到这一点。虽然我很能说会道，但
my strategy for World creation was to
我当时的创业策略是
pitch a brand new tech company because
推销一家全新的科技公司，因为
i' just seen that Social Network movie
我刚看了
with Mark Zuckerberg whereas really I
马克·扎克伯格主演的电影《社交网络》。其实，就像
could have just you as you'd said gone
你刚才说的，我完全可以收购
for Bill's business and presented a
比尔的公司，向
young fresh dig to social First Vision
社交先锋公司（Social First Vision）提出一个年轻而新颖的方案，以此来
um and and mitigated his Risk by and
降低风险。
even if you wanted to do social chain
即使你想做社交链（Social Chain），
you could have started by buying a
你也可以先收购一家年收入
doing 2 million that's high water mark
200万的营销公司。这家公司曾经的巅峰时期
was 4 million and it's hared over the
是400万，虽然过去
last six s years but it still has a core
六年有所下滑，但它仍然拥有核心
team and it's got a 20-year reputation
团队，拥有20年的良好口碑，
and it has a contract with AWS and it
并且与亚马逊云服务（AWS）和
has a contract with Harper Collins and
哈珀·柯林斯出版社都有合作。你会想，
it's like oh yeah we've got all these
哦，我们已经具备了所有这些
things in place you buy that business
条件。你可以先收购这家年收入
that's doing 2 million as a starting
200万的公司作为
point point and then you say now I'm
起点，然后再说，现在我要开始
going to do social chain on top of that
做社交链了。 除此之外，
so now you go from two to you know
现在你可以从两百万起步，
whatever but rather than starting from
但与其从零开始，
absolute scratch you could you could
你
actually start with a couple of million
实际上可以先从几百万美元
of Revenue just by just by going in and
的收入起步，只需与已经
got a starting point two key skills here
拥有一定基础的人达成交易即可。这里有两个关键技能：
the first skill is sales we've talked
第一个技能是销售，我们已经讨论过，
about that you have to be persuasive and
你必须有说服​​力；
the second key skill is even
第二个关键技能是
understanding the structuring of that
理解
deal MH you know and those are two
交易的结构。你知道，这是两件
different things but they're imperative
不同的事，但它们至关重要。
what I've come to learn over the last 5
过去
years is the people in my life that are
五年我逐渐明白，我生命中最
the best wealth creators have those two
优秀的财富创造者都具备这两项
skills they understand how to structure
技能：他们懂得如何构建
a deal and they understand how to sell
交易，也懂得如何推销
the deal yes yeah sales is sales that
交易。是的，销售就是
demand creation the the doing the deal
创造需求的销售，而达成交易
and structuring uh phenomenal skills um
和构建交易结构，这些都是非常了不起的技能。
and everything that you want is on the
你想要的一切都在
other side of a structure that exists so
现有结构的另一边。所以，随着
with scor app uh 20 22 AI comes out and
SCO 2022 年人工智能的出现，
I go oh my God AI changes the
我心想：天哪，人工智能改变了
fundamental nature of this business we
这个行业的本质，我们
need to be on AI I thought the first
需要用上人工智能。我想，
thing I want to do is bring someone onto
我做的第一件事就是找个人加入进来。
the team who is an AI expert so I
团队成员都是人工智能专家，所以我
approach Professor Andy parau who's the
找到了安迪·帕劳教授，他是
head of AI for war University and I say
华威大学的人工智能负责人。我说
we're setting up an AI Advisory Board
我们正在组建一个人工智能顾问委员会，
would you like to be on our AI Advisory
你愿意加入我们吗？
Board here's how much we pay per year
这是我们每年的薪酬，
and would you like to join the board and
你愿意加入吗？
he's like yeah I'll join The Advisory
他欣然同意。
board so he comes and joins our Advisory
于是他加入了我们的顾问委员会，并
board he starts making some
开始就我们
recommendations about how we adapt to
如何应对
the AI challenge we didn't need anyone
人工智能挑战提出一些建议。我们当时觉得他
else that was absolutely perfect he
非常合适，不需要其他人了。他还
brought with him a team of researchers
带来了一个研究团队，负责
of our system as well but what was
我们系统的后端开发。但
interesting is that that happened in two
有趣的是，这一切只用了两周时间。短短
weeks so from two weeks we went from no
两周，我们就从完全没有
AI uh integration to having Professor
人工智能集成，到拥有
Andy poto who's a PhD of AI who's got 25
安迪·帕劳教授——一位拥有25
year background of AI as our adviser
年人工智能经验的人工智能博士——担任我们的顾问。
because we set up an Advisory Board um
因为我们组建了一个顾问委员会，所以
so I just knew what structure to
我很清楚该如何
structure it is MH you know so how do I
构建这个体系。你知道，我该如何开口
say can you help me I need to figure
说“你能帮帮我吗？我需要解决
this out yeah you no but how do you
这个问题”呢？是的，你不知道，但是你该如何向
someone that's you at the very start of
一个像你一样，刚刚踏上人工智能之
their Journey they don't understand all
旅，对人工智能一无所知的人解释呢？ 所有
these they don't have structures I mean
这些都没有固定的架构。我的意思是，
it's hard because in theory you you know
这很难，因为理论上，你知道，
you go talk to a CFO and you basically
你去和首席财务官（CFO）谈谈，基本上是和
talk to an experience CFO who's done a
一位经验丰富的CFO谈，他做过
lot of m&amp;a and you just say oh actually
很多并购，然后你会说，哦，实际上，
do you know it's even wild today you
你知道吗，现在甚至更疯狂，你
don't even need a CFO you go on chat DV
甚至不需要CFO，你只需要在ChatDV上扮演
act as a CFO explain to me what
CFO的角色，向我解释一下，
structures I would use to to do this um
我应该使用什么架构来完成这件事，嗯，
how would I structure a deal how would I
我应该如何构建交易，如何
structure a deal with this explain to me
构建交易，向我解释一下，
I would like to buy a business uh an
我想收购一家公司，一家
existing 20-year-old business I would
已有20年历史的公司，我
like to buy it so that um I don't have
想收购它，这样我就不需要
to pay anything up front and that the
预先支付任何费用，
owners of the business finance my new
公司的所有者会为我的新所有权提供融资，扮演
ownership of the business act as a CFO
CFO的角色，
and advise me on how to do that
并就如何进行这笔交易向我提供建议。
transaction and uh what's amazing is
神奇的是，
chat gbt will do a good job of that or a
Chat GBT在这方面做得很好，或者说是一个
good starting point draft the heads of
很好的起点，
terms you can ask chaty PT to do yeah
你可以让Chaty PT来起草条款清单，是的，起草
dra draft the heads of terms for that
该
deal review the draft of heads of terms
交易的条款清单，审查条款清单草案，
to see if there's any emissions or
看看是否有任何遗漏。 或者
mistakes would you have ch now that
说，如果你现在
you've seen that would you do anything
看到了这些，你会做些
differently yeah I would change this
不同的事情吗？是的，我会改变这一点。我会给
finance director of this company
这家公司的财务总监发一封邮件草稿，
proposing that we acquire the business
提议我们
with no money down right asking for a
零首付收购这家公司，直接要求
meeting yeah yeah isn't it crazy that we
会面。是啊，是啊，我们
live in this new era where the
生活在一个全新的时代，
possibilities in terms of communication
沟通、
storytelling persuasion and the cost of
讲故事、说服以及
um a sale have completely completely
销售成本的可能性都发生了彻底的
changed Dynamics have shifted a is
改变，这难道不疯狂吗？动态已经转变，
changing everything we haven't realized
一切都在改变，而我们还没有意识到这一点，不是吗？
yet have we if you think about how we're
想想我们现在的行为方式，
behaving no no no we haven't quite
不，不，不，我们还没有完全
realized the potential of the technology
意识到我们所拥有技术的潜力。
we have we are like on the movie the
就像电影《
Titanic when they hit the iceberg and
泰坦尼克号》里，他们撞上冰山后，
they're all just like dancing on the
所有人都在冰山上跳舞，
thing and someone says oh it's an
有人说“哦，这是一艘永不
unsinkable ship and the guy with a white
沉没的船”，而那个脸色苍白的人
face uh says it's made of steel it will
说“它是钢铁做的，它会沉没的，
go down it'll sink when I first saw AI
它会沉没的”。当我第一次看到
do what AI does I had that moment of
人工智能发挥它的作用时，我当时的感觉是：
like oh no this changes everything we've
哦不，这改变了一切，我们
just hid an iceberg this is a
刚刚隐藏了一座冰山。这是一项
fundamental general purpose technology
基础性的通用技术，
that is going to change everything it's
它将改变一切。 它将彻底
going to change every industry top to
改变每个行业，
bottom everything's going to have to
一切都将
reorganize itself around an AI landscape
围绕人工智能格局进行重组。
but we're all pretending like it doesn't
但我们都在假装它不存在，假装它没有在发挥作用。
thing isn't doing what it's doing um
嗯，是的，
but yeah there's one thing that AI
人工智能有一点和
disagrees with you on when I say AI I
你的看法不同。我说的人工智能
means Sam Alman um from chat GPT you
指的是 Chat GPT 的创始人 Sam Alman。你
said earlier business is a team sport
之前说过商业是一项团队运动，
now he has a WhatsApp group Sam mman the
现在他建了一个 WhatsApp 群组。Sam Alman 是
founder of chat GPT and in that WhatsApp
Chat GPT 的创始人，他在
group he's got a bet with some friends
群里和朋友们打赌，
that they'll be the first ever one
他们很快就会成为史上第一家一人
person billion doll company soon and
十亿美元公司。
they're guessing on the date of the
他们正在猜测
first ever one person billion dollar
第一家一人十亿美元
company because with AI the team sport
公司出现的时间，因为有了人工智能，团队运动就
becomes you and a large language model
变成了你和一个大型语言模型（
like a chat
比如 Chat
P2 I think that it's directionally
P2）。我认为
correct what he's saying the one person
他的说法方向是对的，一人
AI business will be beaten by the 10
人工智能公司会被十
person AI business and that like yes it
人人工智能公司击败，而且这种情况很
probably will happen it like assuming
可能会发生。当然，假设这种情况真的会
out of course it will happen there will
发生，就会
be a person who creates something using
有人利用人工智能创造出一些东西，
Ai and it and it'll be a standout thing
然后…… 最突出的一点是，
but to replicate that again and again
要一次又一次地复制这种模式，
having what we will see a lot of is five
我们会看到很多这样的团队：由五
person teams with a CEO CTO coo CMO CFO
人组成，包括CEO、CTO、COO、CMO和CFO，他们
who work together as five people doing
五个人
the work of 500 people using AI that'll
利用人工智能完成500人的工作。这
happen definitely and that'll be rep you
肯定会发生，而且会成为一种模式，你
know that'll reproduce but to a degree
知道，它会不断复制。但在某种程度上，
business is is always going to be a team
商业始终是一项团队
sport that
运动，
essentially five or six people will
本质上，五六个人总是能
always beat one because they're they're
战胜一个人，因为他们彼此
they're talking to each other and
交流，从
they're covering different angles and
不同的角度看待问题。
whatever AI strengths AI is very good at
人工智能的优势在于
content but not context and having five
内容，而非背景。如果五
people who share context and create a
个人能够分享背景信息，
context together then the content can
共同构建背景，那么人工智能就可以
happen using ai ai without that context
处理内容。没有背景信息，人工智能
it doesn't know what to do so it doesn't
不知道该做什么，所以它
have any purpose right
现在没有任何意义。
now yeah to a degree it can start to it
是的，在某种程度上，它可以开始发挥作用，但它
still needs a first mover on what is the
仍然需要一个先行者来定义
context why are we doing this in the
背景，明确我们为什么要这样做。所以，这就是关键所在。
um yeah I I agree with you that there is
嗯，我同意你的观点，我们现在正处于一个
like we are at a time in where we can't
无法预见未来的时期，
corner um we don't know what Society
我们不知道社会
will look like but here's a few things I
将会如何发展。 看起来是这样，但我
do know about I do know that as it as it
确实了解一些事情。我知道，就
stands right now humans are great at
目前而言，人类擅长理解
context and AI is good at content and if
语境，而人工智能擅长处理内容。如果
you can provide AI with an amazing
你能为人工智能提供一个绝佳的
context of to what it's meant to be
语境，让它明白自己应该做什么，
doing it will fill in all the blanks but
它就能填补所有空白。但
it needs the context first I know that
它首先需要语境。我知道
Vitality versus functionality AI is
活力与功能之间的关系。人工智能
great at functionality but it needs
在功能方面很出色，但它需要
someone to breathe life force into it
有人赋予它生命力。这种生命力是我们人类赋予
we breathe that we breathe into things
万物的生命力。
so it still needs Vitality even though
所以，即使人工智能能够完成很多功能，它仍然需要活力。
warning that I have for people is that
我要提醒大家的是，
AI is very good at turning you into a
人工智能非常擅长将你变成
Creator or a consumer so it essentially
创造者或消费者。它本质上会
figures you out and it says oh Tik Tok
了解你，然后说：“哦，TikTok，嗯，
huh uh how about we get you to spend 16
不如我们让你在TikTok上花16个
hours on Tik Tok um and and hypnotize
小时吧。”它会催眠
you into spending way longer than you
你，让你在
thought on this thing and the AI is
这个平台上花费比你预想的更长的时间。人工智能
really good at saying we'll drive you
非常擅长引导你达到
someone can consume but it will also
消费的极限，同时也会
drive you to the edges of how much
引导你达到
someone can create and one thing that is
创造的极限。
going to happen in the next few years is
未来几年将会发生的一件事是，
everyone is going to have to make a
每个人都必须有
conscious decision do I want to be a
意识地做出选择：在人工智能领域，我想成为
Creator or a consumer when it in
创造者还是消费者？
relationship to AI because if if you
因为如果你
allow AI to use you it'll just turn you
允许人工智能利用你，它只会把你
into a consumer you'll listen to more
变成消费者，你会听更多
stuff watch more stuff do more like
东西、看更多东西、做更多事、
spend more money because AI is good at
花更多钱，因为人工智能擅长
that or if you use it to build stuff and
这些。或者，如果你用它来创造、
make stuff and produce stuff you will be
制造和生产，你将
because of AI but it's going to divide
凭借人工智能展现出超乎常人的创造力，但这也会将
Society into consumers and
社会分裂成消费者和
creators okay very important
创造者。好了，非常重要的
announcement waited a long time to tell
消息！我等了很久才告诉
you about this last year I launched my
大家，去年我推出了我
very own private Equity Fund called
自己的私募股权基金，名为
flight fund with the aim of investing in
Fligh。  Flight Fund 的目标是投资那些
great companies that are working to
致力于
bring about a better future at flight
创造更美好未来的优秀公司。
fund we're committed to empowering the
我们致力于赋能
most Innovative Founders by providing
最具创新精神的创始人，
not just funding but mentorship guidance
不仅提供资金，还提供导师指导
and a network that fuels their growth
和人脉网络，助力他们的成长。自
since launching the fund we've invested
基金成立以来，我们投资了
in disruptors like SpaceX Zoey Hu whoop
SpaceX、Zoey Hu、Whoop Till 等众多颠覆性企业。
until and many many more and today I'm
今天，我很
excited to announce that flight fund is
高兴地宣布 Flight Fund
now live on Cedar head to the link in
现已上线 Cedar 平台。点击
the description below on this episode it
本期节目下方描述中的链接（链接
and they're called Zoe and I'm coming to
名称为 Flight Fund），即可了解更多关于 Flight Fund 的信息以及我们为何选择与 Cedar 合作。另外，您可能已经知道，我投资的一家公司 Zoe 现在也是本播客的赞助商。
you today with a warning and it's all of
今天我要提醒大家，现在是
those diet companies favorite month of
减肥公司最爱的月份，
the year and that means that you're
这意味着您将会在
across all types of media when it comes
各种媒体上听到大量关于
to diet culture please don't get caught
减肥文化的术语和词汇。请不要盲目跟风，在
health you must listen to experts and
健康方面，您应该听取专家的意见，而
that's exactly what Zoe has Zoe isn't
Zoe 正是这样一家公司。  Zoe 的理念并非
about restriction or removing foods from
限制或从饮食中剔除某些食物，
your diet it's about building
而是帮助你建立
sustainable daily habits that will make
可持续的日常习惯，从而让
your life better forever they'll help
你的生活永远变得更好。他们会帮助
you to discover how eating in the right
你发现如何根据自身情况选择合适的饮食方式，
way for your body with what they call
通过所谓的个性化
personalized nutrition will have you
营养，让你
feeling the benefits almost instantly
几乎立即感受到益处，并且这种益处会持续很久。
and far into the future if you're
如果你
looking to pick up new habits this year
想在今年养成新的习惯，
then use my code
那就使用我的优惠码
ceo1 to get 10% off of your Zoe kit and
ceo1，即可享受 Zoe 套装 10% 的折扣，
do it right now work life balance Daniel
现在就行动吧！工作与生活平衡，丹尼尔，
oh work life balance um is it a thing is
哦，工作与生活平衡，嗯，这真的存在吗？有
there is it possible to be wildly
可能在
successful and not work exceptionally
不付出超乎寻常的努力的情况下获得巨大的成功吗？
hard the people who talk about work life
那些把工作与生活
balance as a as an important thing they
平衡看得非常重要的人，
normally worked their asses off to the
通常都拼命工作，
extent that they almost burnt the
几乎把自己累垮了。然后他们经历了
Jesus moment and then they now spouse
一次顿悟，才在经历了
massive amounts of work that they did
巨大的工作量之后，才开始反思工作与生活平衡的重要性。
and that is typically the pathway
这通常是他们成为
towards the work life balance
工作与生活平衡
Guru so here's the unfortunate thing
大师的必经之路。所以，不幸的是，
you've got to look at what you got to
你必须看看
look at the statistics people who earn
统计数据，看看那些年收入
over 100 Grand uh typically work 55
超过 10 万美元的人。 呃，通常每周工作55个
hours but per week but there's work and
小时，但工作也分很多种，
there's work so you and I work enormous
你我工作
amounts of hours but we're not digging
时间都很长，但我们不是在挖
up roads we're not laying cables we're
路，不是在铺电缆，也不是在
not doing boring repetitive stuff in
做枯燥乏味的重复性工作。在
most cases our work is creativity it's
大多数情况下，我们的工作是创意性的，是
publishing things it's pitching deals
发表作品，是洽谈合作，是
it's sitting there and dragging Den
坐在那里
analyzing what's going on it's doing
分析正在发生的事情，是做
interviews so there's a new style of
采访。所以，现在有一种新的
work so when people get angry about work
工作方式。当人们对工作与
life balance and they say damn it work
生活平衡感到愤怒，说“该死，工作与
life balance has to be a thing it's
生活平衡必须存在”时，
normally because their Association to
通常是因为他们对
work is is that work is such a negative
工作的印象是负面的，认为工作是为了
do in order to make money and when
赚钱而不得不做的事情。当
people say oh I do 55 hours a week and I
人们说“哦，我每周工作55个小时，但我很
love it they go well something's deeply
喜欢”时，他们会说“你肯定有问题，
wrong with you it's like you're toxic
你简直有毒”。是啊，你就是有毒。但
actually it's Apple apples and oranges
实际上，这完全是两码事。是的，
yeah I'm enjoying I'm doing something
我很享受，我做的事情让我
that's deeply fulfilling and passionate
充满成就感和热情，
and I could do it from home and I do it
我可以在家工作，而且我是
online and it's digital and I see my
在线工作的。 它是数字化的，我做这些事的时候总能见到我的
kids all the time while I'm doing it and
孩子，
I actually don't feel like I even work
实际上我感觉自己工作并不
that hard I'm just enjoying it but I am
辛苦，只是在享受其中。但
but I am doing that stuff keep in mind
我确实在做这些事。记住，
this if you're doing a lot of hard work
如果你做了很多辛苦的工作，却
that doesn't develop an asset
没有同时创造资产，
simultaneously it's probably going to
那最终可能会适得其反，
end up toxic you may burn out if you do
你可能会精疲力竭。但如果你做了
a lot of hard work that simultaneously
很多辛苦的工作，同时又
develops an asset the asset value
创造了资产，那么资产的价值
eventually takes over and then you're
最终会占据主导地位，那时你
working completely by choice so simplify
完全是出于自愿而工作。简单来说，
that as if I was a
假设我是一个
10-year-old if you create podcasts and
10岁的孩子，如果你制作播客，
those podcasts go onto YouTube and that
这些播客上传到YouTube，
people can watch them a year later 2
人们可以在一年、
years 3 years later you've developed
两年、三年后观看，你就创造了
something that has a life of of its own
一些拥有自身生命力的东西，
and it's going to continue to create
它会持续创造
value without you having to physically
价值，而无需你亲自参与。
be there so if your work is creating a
所以，如果你的工作创造了一种
byproduct of an asset if you own the
资产的副产品，如果你拥有
company that you started and you own the
自己创办的公司，拥有
shares in that company and that company
这家公司的股份，而这家公司
becomes more and more successful and the
越来越成功，
equity value becomes more and more
股权价值也越来越
valuable your building your work is
高，那么你的工作就是在
creating a valuable asset um if uh like
创造一项有价值的资产。嗯，就像
my wife you renovate horrible properties
我的 你妻子把破旧的房子改造
into amazing properties her work creates
成漂亮的房子，她的工作既能创造
income and an asset simultaneously
收入，又能创造资产。那么，
what's the opposite of that
反之亦然，
where you're working but you're not
你工作却没有
creating any assets well Uber driver I
创造任何资产是什么呢？比如优步司机，我
used to work in McDonald's for two days
以前在麦当劳
I worked in McDonald's as well I I loved
工作过两天，我很喜欢在麦当劳工作。我
created was a deep uh appreciation for
积累的资产是对系统运作的深刻理解。
systems but the the problem with being
但
an Uber driver is that you can actually
优步司机的问题在于，你一天可以
do 16 hour days however at the end of 16
工作16个小时，但16个
hour days that's it you've earned that
小时结束后，你就赚到了那么
amount of money and you've not developed
多钱，却没有积累
any additional asset uh you've just
任何额外的资产。你只是
performed a role um so so you're not
履行了一个职责。所以，你并没有
building simultaneously an asset the
同时积累资产。那些
people who love their work and don't
热爱工作、不会
burn out are the people whose work
精疲力竭的人，他们的工作既能创造
creates income and asset at the same
收入，又能创造资产。
time and they're doing something that's
他们做着自己热爱且充满激情的事情。资产
could be reputation skill deep
可以是声誉、技能、深厚的
skills something that has a life of its
技能，或者拥有
own something that lives beyond the the
自身生命力的东西，或者超越
day that you created it Daniel thank you
你创造的那一天而存在的东西。丹尼尔，非常感谢你。
so much um we do have a closing
嗯，我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个结束的传统。 上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
客人给下一位
guest not knowing who they're leaving it
客人留了一个问题，但他并不知道这个问题是留给谁的。
for and the question left for you
留给你的问题是：
is what is the one thing you'd wish
你希望年轻时就
you'd known about sex and relationships
了解的关于性和人际关系的一件事是什么？
in your youth that you later
你后来才
learned the the a lot of the enjoyment
明白，
of sex is the relationship that you're
性爱的乐趣很大程度上来自于你与对方建立的关系，而不仅仅是性爱本身。
moment um so in my youth I saw sex as a
嗯，在我年轻的时候，我把性看作一件
standalone thing that was a
独立的事情，一件与生活脱节的
compartmentalized thing and essentially
事情。基本上，
you know if you can pick up and have sex
如果你能随便找个人发生性关系，
then that's a win but you discover
那就算成功了。但你
prettyy quickly that it's actually empty
很快就会发现，这其实是空虚的、
and meaningless and and also awkward and
毫无意义的，而且
really awkward the following day and all
第二天会非常尴尬等等。
of that sort of stuff whereas when you
然而，当你
find someone who you really love and
找到一个你真正爱的人，
you're building a life with them and
你们一起建立生活，一起
you're uh sharing highs and lows with
分享喜怒哀乐，你们之间建立了
them and there's a deep connection then
深厚的联系时，性就变成了
almost like an ingredient that is
一种
infused through all of that um so it's
贯穿所有这一切的元素。嗯，它
it's very linked to love and connection
与爱、联结
and life does that fit into your
和生活息息相关。这符合你关于
framework of function functionality and
功能、活力和
vitality yeah so so it's either done
生命力的框架吗？是的。所以，要么 性行为可能是
from a space of love and life force
出于爱和生命
energy or it's done as something that's
能量，也可能是出于
functional probably something that
功能性目的，
people have to go through to
人们可能需要经历才能体会到。
experientially learn I think that um you
我觉得，嗯，
know that there's you know the the other
你知道，对
thing for for young men is that that
年轻男性来说，
that the the way that sex happens for a
性行为的体验方式与
man is different to how it happens for a
女性不同。
woman and that you you know you may have
你可能有一种
a feeling or I had a feeling when I was
感觉，或者我
uh a young young guy in my late teens
年轻的时候，大概十几岁到二十出头，觉得
early 20s that I was unlovable and
自己不讨人喜欢，没有
unattractive and um and that no one
吸引力，没人
would want to have sex with me so I'd
会想和我发生性关系，所以我得用搭讪之类的手段
have to trick them into you know having
来骗他们。
that and actually when I built my
但实际上，当我建立起
confidence and when I built who I was as
自信，塑造了自我
a person then it actually became much
之后，性行为就变成了一种
more of a natural experience um and uh
更加自然的体验。嗯，
I'm not sure what I'm trying to say here
我不太确定我在这里想表达什么，
it's not energy you were describing the
你描述的不是那种能量，
where you don't necessarily need the
你不一定需要
sale yeah with or without you energy
推销，是的，无论有没有能量，性行为都会
that definitely happen
发生。
um yeah so you know when I became an
嗯，所以，你知道，当我成为一名
entrepreneur and I was speaking in front
企业家之后…… 在
of big audiences and wrote bestselling
大型演讲场合发表演讲，撰写畅销
books and all of those sorts of things I
书等等，这些经历让我
had much more With or Without You energy
拥有了更多“有你或没有你”的能量。
and the beauty was is that when I met my
美妙的是，当我遇到我
wife I was in a really great space where
妻子时，我正处于一个非常好的状态，
I you know she was she had with or
你知道，她也拥有“有你或
without you energy I had wither without
没有你”的能量，我也拥有同样的
you energy and we recognized each other
能量。我们彼此都意识到对方是
as um great an amazing force of
绝佳的
collaboration and partnership and we
合作伙伴，我们
realized that one and one would be 11 in
意识到在这种情况下，1加1等于11。
this situation and and actually it was
事实上，那是
it was uh a magic moment I knew I was
一个神奇的时刻，
going to marry her within about 12 hours
大约12小时后，我就知道我会娶她。
Daniel thank you so much for your time
丹尼尔，非常感谢您抽出时间。
you have so many incredible books um
您有很多非常棒的书，
that are real smashit and it's funny
而且
that these books are growing in
这些书非常成功。有趣的是，尽管时代在变化，但这些书仍然越来越
popularity despite the fact that times
受欢迎，
are changing which I think speaks to how
我认为这说明了
Timeless they are and you create a lot
它们的永恒性。您创作了很多
of content so I think if people want to
内容，所以我认为，如果人们想持续
hear more from you on an ongoing Bas
听到您的更多内容，
basis and continue with this sort of
并继续
Education that we've had today then they
我们今天所进行的这种教育，那么他们
should definitely check out your social
绝对应该关注您的社交
media channels because I followed them
媒体账号，因为我已经关注了。
and the way that you create content is
您创作内容的方式和
very much like the way you speak you're
您说话的方式非常相似。 你
very good at taking large complex ideas
非常擅长将复杂的大型概念
distilling them down into sort of simple
提炼成简单
relatable understandable Concepts and
易懂、易于理解的概念，并以
that's actionable and accessible that's
切实可行且易于接受的方式传递给人们。
what your books do that's what your
你的书和你的
content does and that's what you do so
内容正是如此，而你在这方面也做得非常出色。所以，
well so thank you Daniel for being on my
丹尼尔，非常感谢你做客我的
show that is a huge compliment coming
节目，这对我来说是莫大的赞美。
from you thank you oh no you're you're a
谢谢！哦，不，你真是这方面的
master of what you do so I appreciate
专家！丹尼尔，我非常感谢
you Daniel thank you
你！谢谢！
cheers the key to growing a business is
企业发展的关键在于
making sure that it's scalable and this
确保其可扩展性，而这需要
platforms early in the game to support
尽早整合到合适的平台来支持业务
your growth a platform that's helped me
增长。Shopify 就是一个帮助我
and my team to do this is Shopify who
和我的团队实现这一目标的平台，
I'm sure you know by now because they do
我相信你现在应该已经了解它了，因为他们
sponsor this podcast Shopify is a
赞助了这个播客。Shopify 是一个
Commerce platform revolutionizing
电商平台，正在革新
millions of businesses worldwide we
全球数百万家企业的运营模式。我们
recently launched our second version of
最近在 Shopify 上推出了第二版
the diio conversation cards on Shopify
Diio 对话卡片，如果没有 Shopify，这一切都
which would not have been possible
不可能实现。
without Shopify when I started
当我开始做
podcasting an online store was the
播客的时候，开网店是
furthest thing from my mind but now
我最不愿想到的事情，但现在，
thanks to how simple it is to use the
多亏了 Shopify
platform it's made this whole process so
平台的便捷易用，整个过程变得
unbelievably easy it's actually the
无比轻松。 实际上，Shopify 的
internet's best converting checkout 36%
结账转化率是互联网上最高的，
better on average compared to other
平均比其他
leading Commerce platforms if you guys
领先的电商平台高出 36%。如果你
haven't tried Shopify on your business
还没在你的企业主那里试过 Shopify，
owners go and try it now because you can
现在就去试试吧，因为你可以
sign up for a $1 per month trial period
注册一个每月只需 1 美元的试用期，
just by heading to shopify.com
只需访问 shopify.com
Bartlet and you can get started for
Bartlet 即可开始使用。
[Music]
[音乐]
$1
1 美元